{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Neurotoxins","incorrectAnswers":["Neurovenoms","Endotoxins","Endovenoms"],"question":"What is the name given to a poison that acts on the nervous system?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Metallica","incorrectAnswers":["Alice Cooper","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American heavy metal band released the studio album 'Death Magnetic'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"vibrations and oscillations in the Sun","incorrectAnswers":["origin of life","earthquakes","alternative method of massage, manipulative therapy|therapy or pressure on certain points of the sole of the feet as a means of relieving nervous tension"],"question":"What is Helioseismology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"BMW","incorrectAnswers":["Harley Davidson","Mercedez-Benz","Porsche"],"question":"Which motoring brand is associated with the marketing slogan 'The Ultimate Driving Machine'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Ring of Fire","incorrectAnswers":["MacArthur Park","Can't Get Used to Losing You","Landslide"],"question":"Which song, originally recorded by Johnny Cash, was later covered by Wall of Voodoo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Gustave Flaubert","incorrectAnswers":["Anatole France","Guy de Maupassant","Charles Perrault"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Bouvard et Pécuchet'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Pennsylvania","incorrectAnswers":["Ohio","Indiana","Maryland"],"question":"Which U.S. state has communities called Lititz, Ephrata, and Strasburg in its Amish Country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Saudi Arabia","incorrectAnswers":["Guinea-Bissau","Samoa","Slovakia"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.sa' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ukraine","incorrectAnswers":["Tajikistan","Poland","Lithuania"],"question":"Kyiv is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The FSB","incorrectAnswers":["The EU","The WHO","Interpol"],"question":"What organisation is based in the  Lubjlyanka building?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mythical animals","incorrectAnswers":["Blackberries","Allergies","Flags"],"question":"What is Cryptozoology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Arizona/Nevada","incorrectAnswers":["California/Nevada","Utah/Colorado","Utah/Nevada"],"question":"On which state border is the Hoover Dam? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Orson Welles","incorrectAnswers":["Louis Figaro","Jack Thomas","Eugene Lamonde"],"question":"Whose radio production of War Of The World's caused panic in America in 1938?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Darwin","incorrectAnswers":["Percy Bysshe Shelley","H. Rider Haggard","Robert Louis Stevenson"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Descent of Man And Selection in Relation to Sex'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Foreshortening","incorrectAnswers":["Isometric Projection","Topomorphism","Skewed Perspective"],"question":"Which art technique can be described as \"Reducing or distorting in order to represent three-dimensional space as perceived by the eye\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Bacchus","incorrectAnswers":["Apollo","Zeus","Hermes"],"question":"Which wine god's orgiastic worship was suppressed by the Roman Senate in the 180s BC?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"El Dorado","incorrectAnswers":["Atlantis","Shangri-La","Camelot"],"question":"What fabled city was German adventurer Philipp Von Hutten searching for when he explored South America in the 1540s?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Shinto","incorrectAnswers":["Buddhism","Taoism","Hinduism"],"question":"What is the name of the Japanese religion that has many sects including Fukko and Watarai?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Animal behaviour","incorrectAnswers":["The Earth's atmosphere","Glaciers","Friction and lubrication"],"question":"What is Ethology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1997","incorrectAnswers":["1989","1993","2001"],"question":"In which year was Good Will Hunting released?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"James Whistler","incorrectAnswers":["Andy Warhol","Grant Wood","Eddie Harold"],"question":"Which american artist is known for a portrait of his mother?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Fresh Prince of Bel-Air","incorrectAnswers":["Seinfeld","Friends","Home Improvement"],"question":"What was the name of the popular '90s sitcom starring Will Smith?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Arthur Conan Doyle","incorrectAnswers":["Agatha Christie","Oscar Wilde","George Orwell"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Adventures of Sherlock Holmes'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The Hay","incorrectAnswers":["The Manger","A Donkey","The Stars"],"question":"In the Christmas carol 'Away in a Manger', what was the little Lord Jesus asleep on?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A leader tries to expand his empire while a poor barber tries to avoid persecution.","incorrectAnswers":["Two men join in an uneasy alliance against a third to find gold buried in a remote cemetery.","A weatherman finds himself trapped in a small town as he lives the same day over and over again.","A surgeon rescues a disfigured man who is mistreated while scraping a living as a side-show freak."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie The Great Dictator?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Rolling Stones","incorrectAnswers":["Black","Sticky Fingers","Brown Sugar"],"question":"What was the title of the first album released by The Rolling Stones?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1989","incorrectAnswers":["1984","1994","1999"],"question":"When did the scientist Tim Berners-Lee invent the World Wide Web?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Moscow Treaty","incorrectAnswers":["The Berlin Treaty","The Warsaw Treaty","The Yalta Treaty"],"question":"1970 Saw Which Treaty Between USSR & West Germany","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Appendix","incorrectAnswers":["Bowel","Spleen","Pancreas"],"question":"Which fingerlike projection is attached to the large intestine?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Hooked on a Feeling\" by B.J. Thomas","incorrectAnswers":["\"Immigrant Song\" by Led Zeppelin","\"What I Got\" by Sublime","\"American Pie\" by Don McLean"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Ooga-chaka, Ooga-ooga / Ooga-chaka, Ooga-ooga...\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Austria","Benin","North Africa"],"question":"Crêpes are most associated with which part of the world?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Blue","incorrectAnswers":["Green","Gold","Black"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of United Kingdom?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Tommy Lee","incorrectAnswers":["Nikki Sixx","Vince Neil","Mick Mars"],"question":"Who was Pamela Anderson married to before her brief marriage to Kid Rock?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beach Boys","incorrectAnswers":["Swans","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American rock band released the song 'God Only Knows'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Snowflake","incorrectAnswers":["Buttercup","Pumpkin","Cupcake"],"question":"What slang term refers to a very sensitive person who is easily offended?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Elizabeth I","incorrectAnswers":["James III","Victoria","Henry VIII"],"question":"Who ruled England at the time of Shakespeare?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Green","incorrectAnswers":["Nine","Red","Six"],"question":"In French, what is the meaning of the word 'vert'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"dietetics","incorrectAnswers":["intonation in speech","in ethics, duty","fossils of ancient life"],"question":"What is Sitiology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Apple ","incorrectAnswers":["Grape","Banana","Cherry"],"question":"Blanche Ames, Lord Lambourne and Willis Williams are all varieties of _________","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Monrovia","incorrectAnswers":["Brazzaville","Ulaanbaatar","Nur-Sultan"],"question":"What is the capital city of Liberia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Paul Cézanne","incorrectAnswers":["Henri Rousseau","‎‎Johannes Vermeer","Mark Rothko"],"question":"Which artist painted \"The Bathers\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jonathan Swift","incorrectAnswers":["William Godwin","Voltaire","Henry Fielding"],"question":"Who wrote \"Gullivers Travels\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"12 Angry Men","incorrectAnswers":["American History X","All About Eve","Rear Window"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'The jury in a murder trial is frustrated by a member whose caution forces them to consider the evidence.'","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Life is a banquet, and most poor suckers are starving to death!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"That is so fetch.\"","\"I am big! It's the pictures that got small.\"","\"Mother of mercy, is this the end of Rico?\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Auntie Mame'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Penélope Cruz","incorrectAnswers":["Amy Adams","Uma Thurman","Cameron Diaz"],"question":"Which actress has played roles in films including Pirates of the Caribbean: On Stranger Tides and Volver?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Cleveland Browns","incorrectAnswers":["Cleveland Whitesox","Cleveland SC","Cleveland A's"],"question":"Which of these is an American Football team based in Cleveland?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Troy","incorrectAnswers":["Athens","Rome","Jerusalem"],"question":"What ancient city is also known as Ilium?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Sri Lanka","incorrectAnswers":["Madagascar","Belize","Fiji"],"question":"Which island nation has been called the 'teardrop of India' due to its location and shape?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Leonardo DiCaprio","incorrectAnswers":["Ralph Fiennes","Brian Cox","Kiefer Sutherland"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Titanic and Inception?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The United States","incorrectAnswers":["Korea","China","Germany"],"question":"Where were fortune cookies invented?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Mary I","incorrectAnswers":["Mary II","Maria I","Marie Antoinette"],"question":"Which Queen of England was known as Bloody Mary?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Flea","incorrectAnswers":["Tick","Rat","Dust Mite"],"question":"What type of animal is pulex irritants?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1958","incorrectAnswers":["1934","1942","1971"],"question":"When was the pacemaker invented?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Green Bay Packers","incorrectAnswers":["The Dallas Cowboys","The Pittsburgh Steelers","The New England Patriots"],"question":"Which NFL team, known for its fans' distinctive cheese wedge hats, is also nicknamed \"Cheeseheads\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Linguine","incorrectAnswers":["Orecchiette","Ditalini","Gemelli"],"question":"Which pasta's name means 'Little tongues'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["Asia","North America","South America"],"question":"Which is the Earth's second largest continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Rocky","incorrectAnswers":["Amélie","The Deer Hunter","Schindler's List"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A small-time boxer gets a chance to fight the world heavyweight champion.'","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Green Book","incorrectAnswers":["Platoon","V for Vendetta","The Dark Knight"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A working-class bouncer becomes the driver of an African-American classical pianist.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Pyrenees","incorrectAnswers":["The Alps","The Urals","The Pennines"],"question":"What is the name of the mountain chain separating Spain from France?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"John le Carré","incorrectAnswers":["Agatha Christie","Georges Simenon","Charles Dickens"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Constant Gardener'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Botswana","incorrectAnswers":["Estonia","Saudi Arabia","Micronesia"],"question":"Gaborone is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tubular pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Soup pasta","Shaped pasta","Ribbon pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is gomiti?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Super heavyweight","incorrectAnswers":["Flyweight","Heavyweight","Maxweight"],"question":"What is the heaviest class of weight-lifting?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Egypt","incorrectAnswers":["Cambodia","Turkey","Benin"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served Kushari?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A cyborg must protect a ten-year-old boy from a more powerful cyborg.","incorrectAnswers":["A criminal pleads insanity and is admitted to a mental institution.","An NYPD officer tries to save his wife taken hostage by terrorists during a Christmas party.","A car salesman's inept crime falls apart due to his and his henchmen's bungling."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Terminator 2: Judgment Day?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Snooker","Hockey","Cycling"],"question":"With which sport is John McEnroe associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Pigs ","incorrectAnswers":["Sheep","Cows","Cats"],"question":"Which animal is used to sniff out truffles?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Love means never having to say you're sorry.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Greed, for lack of a better word, is good.\"","\"May the Force be with you.\"","\"This is the day you will always remember as the day you almost caught Captain Jack Sparrow!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Love Story'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Right Said Fred","incorrectAnswers":["Vanilla Ice","Musical Youth","Rob Base & DJ E-Z Rock"],"question":"Who had a hit in 1991 with I'm Too Sexy?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Onion","incorrectAnswers":["Pepper","Tomato","Garlic"],"question":"What do you add to a martini to make it a Gibson?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Pride and Prejudice","incorrectAnswers":["The Fault in Our Stars","Ship of Fools","War and Peace"],"question":"In which book does 'George Wickham' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Flail","incorrectAnswers":["Spear","Axe","Sword"],"question":"Which of these was not a type of Viking weapon?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Spanish Flu","incorrectAnswers":["Swine Flu","SARS","Coronavirus"],"question":"What was the name of the pandemic which killed over 1% of the world's population in 1918?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Exchange Rate","incorrectAnswers":["GDP","Inflation Rate","Currency Ratio"],"question":"What is the term for the value of one currency in relation to another currency?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Dead Sea Scrolls","incorrectAnswers":["The Rosetta Stone","The Nag Hammadi Library","The Gospel of Judas"],"question":"Which ancient artifact was discovered in 1947 in caves in the Qumran region of the West Bank?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Jack","incorrectAnswers":["Ensign","Pennant","Burgee"],"question":"What is the name of the flag flown on a short pole at the bow of a ship?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Sense and Sensibility","incorrectAnswers":["Pride and Prejudice","Emma","Mansfield Park"],"question":"Which novel by Jane Austen ends with sisters Marianne & Elinor Dashwood getting married?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Triton","incorrectAnswers":["Hercules","Jason","Perseus"],"question":"Who is the son of Poseidon in Greek mythology and the undersea king in a Disney movie?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1921","incorrectAnswers":["1940","1951","1968"],"question":"In which year was the vaccine for tuberculosis created?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Karl Marx","incorrectAnswers":["Ludwig Wittgenstein","Socrates","Friedrich Nietzsche"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Religion is the sign of the oppressed ... it is the opium of the people'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Shaped pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Strand pasta","Tubular pasta","Ribbon pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is campanelle?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Drie","incorrectAnswers":["Trois","Tres","Zeven"],"question":"In Dutch, what is the word for for 'three'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"George S. Patton","incorrectAnswers":["David Dixon Porter","George Elliot","Philip Sheridan"],"question":"Which of these people was a United States Army general during World War II?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Cratchett","incorrectAnswers":["Poorboy","Thompson","Squalor"],"question":"In 'A Christmas Carol'', what is Tiny Tim's surname","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Port ","incorrectAnswers":["Vodka","Brandy","Amaretto"],"question":"Which drink comes in Ruby and Tawny varieties?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Seize the day","incorrectAnswers":["The time are changing, and we change in them","The act done by me against my will is not my act","A beard doesn't make one a philosopher"],"question":"How does that Latin phrase 'Carpe diem' translate into English?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The sh in 'shop'","incorrectAnswers":["The n in 'no'","The k in 'sock'","The j in 'juice'"],"question":"In phonetics, which of these is an example of a fricative sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Bravo","incorrectAnswers":["Boot","Ball","Baby"],"question":"What word is used in the NATO Phonetic Alphabet for the letter B?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A pack","incorrectAnswers":["A shrewdness","A brood","A rag"],"question":"What is the word for a group of hounds?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"December 6th","incorrectAnswers":["December 18th","December 25th","December 26th"],"question":"When is the Feast of St. Nicholas?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Hawaii","incorrectAnswers":["California","Alaska","Washington"],"question":"Which U.S. state has a Volcanoes National Park that includes the summit of a 13,677-foot high volcano?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sean Connery","incorrectAnswers":["Daniel Craig","Roger Moore","Timothy Dalton"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in From Russia With Love?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Y2K","incorrectAnswers":["Bug2000","Trojan Horse","The Millennial Worm"],"question":"What was the nickname given to the possible computer bug that caused worldwide concern leading up to the year 2000?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Trois","incorrectAnswers":["Tre","Drie","Noir"],"question":"In French, what is the word for for 'three'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sean Connery","incorrectAnswers":["Roger Moore","Timothy Dalton","Pierce Brosnan"],"question":"Which James Bond actor played the role in Dr. No and Diamonds Are Forever?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Bryan Singer","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed X-Men?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Batman","incorrectAnswers":["Rocky","Die Hard","The Good, the Bad and the Ugly"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'When a serial killer murders key political figures, a vigilante is forced to intervene.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Spinning wheels","incorrectAnswers":["Candles","Pillows","Dolls"],"question":"What household objects did Sleeping Beauty's parents try to have burned?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Chicago Cubs","incorrectAnswers":["Chicago Capitals","Chicago Giants","Chicago Spurs"],"question":"Which of these is a baseball team based in Chicago?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jennifer Connelly","incorrectAnswers":["Rachel Weisz","Frances Fisher","Salma Hayek"],"question":"Which actress has appeared in films including 'Requiem for a Dream' in 2000 and 'Hulk' in 2003?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"George V","incorrectAnswers":["Elizabeth II","James III","Charles IV"],"question":"Who was the first Windsor monarch of the UK?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Nine Inch Nails","incorrectAnswers":["The White Stripes","Creedence Clearwater Revival","Miley Cyrus"],"question":"Which artist first recorded 'Hurt', which was later covered by Johnny Cash?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Scotland","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","Romania","Mexico"],"question":"Which country is associated with the drink whisky?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Odin","incorrectAnswers":["Thor","Freyr","Loki"],"question":"In Norse mythology, who is the ruler of all gods?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Pacific","incorrectAnswers":["Atlantic","Indian","Antarctic"],"question":"Which Is The Largest Ocean?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Diwali","incorrectAnswers":["Holi","Dusshera","Navaratri"],"question":"What is the name of the Hindu festival of lights?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"David Ben-Gurion","incorrectAnswers":["Menachem Begin","Yitzhak Rabin","Ariel Sharon"],"question":"Who was the first Prime Minister of Israel?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Justinian I","incorrectAnswers":["William the Conqueror","Cyrus the Great","George Washington"],"question":"Which influential historical person was Emperor of the Eastern Roman Empire?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1976","incorrectAnswers":["1966","1971","1981"],"question":"Rocky was released in which year?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dante Alighieri","incorrectAnswers":["Giovanni Boccaccio","Agatha Christie","Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Inferno'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Iced Tea ","incorrectAnswers":["Green Tea","Peppermint Tea","Afternoon Tea"],"question":"Which contribution to tea culture was introduced at the St. Louis world fair in 1904","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Green Bay Packers","incorrectAnswers":["Green Bay Raiders","Green Bay Canucks","Green Bay Mets"],"question":"Which of these is an American Football team based in Green Bay?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"George III","incorrectAnswers":["Henry I","Edward II","Anne"],"question":"Who was the monarch of The United Kingdom during the time period 1760-1820?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Burkina Faso","incorrectAnswers":["Nigeria","Ivory Coast","São Tomé and Príncipe"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Togo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I feel the need - the need for speed!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Bond. James Bond.\"","\"Tell 'em to go out there with all they got and win just one for the Gipper.\"","\"Louis, I think this is the beginning of a beautiful friendship.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Top Gun'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Boxing","incorrectAnswers":["Cycling","Cricket","Ice Hockey"],"question":"With which sport is Henry Cooper associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ethiopia ","incorrectAnswers":["Syria","Egypt","Azerbaijan"],"question":"Which country was previously called Abyssinia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"study of the mouth and its diseases","incorrectAnswers":["music in society, usually non-western music","illness","embryos"],"question":"What is Stomatology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Badminton","Surfing","Motor racing"],"question":"With which sport is Andy Murray associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Dickens","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Joseph Conrad","Henryk Sienkiewicz"],"question":"Which author wrote 'David Copperfield'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Goliath","incorrectAnswers":["Samson","Abraham","Moses"],"question":"In the biblical story, who did David defeat using a sling and some pebbles?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Constantine","incorrectAnswers":["Justinian","Claudius","Julius"],"question":"Who Was The First Christian Emperor Of Rome?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Anthony Bourdain ","incorrectAnswers":["Michel Roux Jr","Gordon Ramsay","Heston Blumenthal"],"question":"Which Chef Wrote 'Kitchen Confidential'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Laika","incorrectAnswers":["Albert","Pirouette","Querida"],"question":"What was the name of the first animal (a dog) to orbit the earth?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"King of Macedonia and military leader.","incorrectAnswers":["Principal figure of Jainism.","Leader of the Russian Revolution and new Communist regime from 1917 to 1924.","French military and political leader."],"question":"Which of the following describes Alexander the Great?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"disease classification","incorrectAnswers":["the characteristics of the skull","the theological study of redemption","mental processes in living creatures"],"question":"What is Nosology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Upperclassman","incorrectAnswers":["Sophomore","Freshman","Senior"],"question":"In the USA, what term is used to refer to a student in the last 2 years of high school or college?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Carpenters","incorrectAnswers":["Builders","Plumbers","Electricians"],"question":"What do Karen, Richard and Joseph all have in common","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"A Palette","incorrectAnswers":["An eisel","A square","A pitcher"],"question":"What is the word given to a flat board used by a painter to mix and hold colors?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"600","incorrectAnswers":["Men","Doomed","Storm"],"question":"Complete the following line from 'The Charge of the Light Brigade' poem: 'All in the valley of Death rode the ___'","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Sachertorte","incorrectAnswers":["Strudel","Kringle","Cannoli"],"question":"What is the name of a dessert which is a chocolate gateaux filled with apricot jam and topped with chocolate icing?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Focus","incorrectAnswers":["2CV","XK120","Corolla"],"question":"Which of these is a model of car made by Ford?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Led Zeppelin","incorrectAnswers":["The Doors","The Rolling Stones","The Beatles"],"question":"What is the name of the band that wrote and performed the song \"Kashmir\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"one of two main branches of soil science","incorrectAnswers":["wood","Unidentified flying object phenomena","microorganisms"],"question":"What is Pedology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Adrian IV","incorrectAnswers":["Mark II","Alfred I","Clemence II"],"question":"Who Was The Only British Pope?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Oldsmobile","incorrectAnswers":["Chevrolet","Ford","Nissan"],"question":"Which car model made the Cutlass Ciera?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Cure","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Snow Patrol"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'Kiss Me, Kiss Me, Kiss Me'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Great Escape","incorrectAnswers":["La Haine","Kill Bill: Vol. 1","There Will Be Blood"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'Prisoners of war plan to escape from a German camp during World War II.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Spain","incorrectAnswers":["Monaco","Switzerland","Luxembourg"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Andorra?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Caterpillar","incorrectAnswers":["A Codling","A Chick","A Spiderling"],"question":"A young butterfly is known as what?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Of all the gin joints in all the towns in all the world, she walks into mine.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"A boy's best friend is his mother.\"","\"Life is a banquet, and most poor suckers are starving to death!\"","\"What a dump.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Casablanca'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Linus Torvalds","incorrectAnswers":["Lin Wux","Lionel Uxworth","Linda Uxbridge"],"question":"Who is the Linux operating system named after?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Papaya","incorrectAnswers":["Mango","Kiwi","Banana"],"question":"Which of these fruits is native to Central America?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["Germany","Brazil","New Zealand"],"question":"In which country would you find the city of Florence?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Boar","incorrectAnswers":["A Macho","A Bull","A Hob"],"question":"What is the word for a male pig?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Post-Impressionism","incorrectAnswers":["Crystal Cubism","Romanticism","Northern Renaissance"],"question":"The painting \"Cafe Terrace at Night\" by ‎Vincent van Gogh is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The Middle East","incorrectAnswers":["Southeast Asia","North America","Europe"],"question":"From which part of the world do cherries originate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Finland","incorrectAnswers":["Thailand","Cuba","Canada"],"question":"Which country is also known as Suomi?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bering Strait","incorrectAnswers":["Strait of Gibraltar","Bosporus Strait","Strait of Malacca"],"question":"Which strait lies between Alaska and Russia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"101 Dalmatians","incorrectAnswers":["Lady and the Tramp","The Fox and the Hound","The Aristocats"],"question":"In what Disney animated film is Cruella de Vil the villainess who kidnaps a group of animals?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Syria","incorrectAnswers":["Finland","Morocco","Somalia"],"question":"Damascus is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"England ","incorrectAnswers":["The Netherlands","Belgium","France"],"question":"Which Country Is The Source Of Stilton Cheese?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Green","incorrectAnswers":["White","Blue","Maroon"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Jamaica?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Arthur Conan Doyle","incorrectAnswers":["Agatha Christie","Oscar Wilde","George Orwell"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Case-Book of Sherlock Holmes'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Toronto","incorrectAnswers":["New York","London","Minneapolis-St Paul"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Canada?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"A Spare","incorrectAnswers":["A Strike","A Near","A Close"],"question":"In Bowling What Is The Term For Knocking Down All Ten Pins With 2 Consecutive Balls?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Toto, I've a feeling we're not in Kansas anymore.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Frankly, my dear, I don't give a damn.\"","\"I’ve been a poor man and I’ve been a rich man. And I choose rich every f****** time!\"","\"I love the smell of napalm in the morning.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'The Wizard of Oz'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"North America","incorrectAnswers":["India","Africa","China"],"question":"Where in the world are cranberries originally from?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Jupiter","incorrectAnswers":["Saturn","Uranus","Neptune"],"question":"What is the biggest planet in the Solar System?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1976","incorrectAnswers":["1966","1971","1981"],"question":"Taxi Driver was released in which year?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Quark","incorrectAnswers":["Atom","Proton","Neutron"],"question":"What is the smallest particle known to exist?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indlamu","incorrectAnswers":["Hula","Tango","Flamenco"],"question":"What is the traditional dance of the Zulu people of South Africa?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"6","incorrectAnswers":["4","8","10"],"question":"How many pockets are on a regulation pool table?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Rome","incorrectAnswers":["Athens","Jerusalem","Istanbul"],"question":"What ancient metropolis was built on seven hills, including Viminal and Aventine?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Cherry Blossom","incorrectAnswers":["Lily","Weeping Redbud","Dandelion"],"question":"What is often regarded as the national flower of Japan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Montreal Impact","incorrectAnswers":["Montreal Broncos","Montreal Mets","Montreal Bruins"],"question":"Which of these is a soccer team based in Montreal?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Zimbabwe","incorrectAnswers":["Zambia","Angola","Malawi"],"question":"Which of these countries borders South Africa?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Unforgiven","incorrectAnswers":["The Crying Game","A Few Good Men","Howards End"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1992?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Celts","incorrectAnswers":["Huns","Gauls","Jutes"],"question":"Halloween originated from a festival celebrated by what ancient European people?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"White","incorrectAnswers":["Orange","Blue","Yellow"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Turkey?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Oasis","Queen","The Clash"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Helter Skelter'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The 1963 assassination of President John F. Kennedy","incorrectAnswers":["The 1969 Manson Family murders","The 1974 abduction of heiress Patricia Hearst","The 1979 Jonestown mass suicide"],"question":"Which of the following famous criminal cases was solved by the use of ballistic evidence?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bridgetown","incorrectAnswers":["Kingstown","Victoria","Dublin"],"question":"What is the capital city of Barbados?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Mahershala Ali","incorrectAnswers":["Jeff Bridges","Lucas Hedges","Dev Patel"],"question":"Who won the 2016 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actor for playing the role of Juan in Moonlight?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Swimming","Sailing","Cycling"],"question":"Which sport is played at The Davis Cup?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Buster Poindexter","incorrectAnswers":["Bow Wow Wow","Crash Test Dummies","Andrea True Connection"],"question":"'Hot, Hot, Hot' was a one hit wonder in 1987 by which artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Arthur Conan Doyle","incorrectAnswers":["Agatha Christie","Oscar Wilde","George Orwell"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Lost World'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"SMTP","incorrectAnswers":["FTP","HTTP","DNS"],"question":"Which protocol is used to send and receive emails?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tea ","incorrectAnswers":["Juice","Beer","Wine"],"question":"What Would You Be Drinking If You Were Given Earl Grey?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tonga","incorrectAnswers":["Andorra","Kyrgyzstan","Somalia"],"question":"Nuku'alofa is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Drag","incorrectAnswers":["Thrust","Gravity","Lift"],"question":"What is the name of the force that resists the forward motion of a moving airplane?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Bull","incorrectAnswers":["A Drone","A Tiercel","A Rooster"],"question":"A male sea lion is known as what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Fergalicious\" by Fergie and will.i.am.","incorrectAnswers":["\"Let's Go Crazy\" by Prince and The Revolution","\"Old Man\" by Neil Young","\"All Star\" by Smash Mouth"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Listen up, y'all, 'cause this is it, the beat that I'm bangin' is de-li-cious.\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Protection and mating displays","incorrectAnswers":["Digging and climbing","Attracting prey and communication","Receiving electromagnetic signals"],"question":"What was the purpose of the horns and plates that adorned some dinosaurs?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Puzzles","incorrectAnswers":["Disease classification","Life in outer space","World War II"],"question":"What is enigmatology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Stranglers","incorrectAnswers":["Sex Pistols","Violent Femmes","T. Rex"],"question":"Who sang 'No More Heroes'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hajj","incorrectAnswers":["Umrah","Haram","Ziyarat"],"question":"What is the name for the Islamic pilgrimage to Mecca?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"William Shakespeare","incorrectAnswers":["Arthur C. Clarke","Isaac Newton","Enid Blyton"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Much Ado About Nothing'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Yemen","incorrectAnswers":["Estonia","Chile","Guatemala"],"question":"In which country would you find the Old Walled City of Shibam?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Fish","incorrectAnswers":["Mountain range","Fighter jet","Hurricane"],"question":"Fandible, lateral line, and dorsal fin are parts of a what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The time are changing, and we change in them","incorrectAnswers":["What is said is done","The act done by me against my will is not my act","Mutiny against mutanous senators"],"question":"How does that Latin phrase 'Tempora mutantur et nos mutamur in illis' translate into English?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"How to encode and decode secret messages","incorrectAnswers":["Animal diseases","Sacred texts","Burial grounds"],"question":"What is cryptology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Alexander Graham Bell","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Edison","Nikola Tesla","Benjamin Franklin"],"question":"Who created an audiometer to detect vestigial hearing in the deaf, among other inventions?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Uniform Resource Locator","incorrectAnswers":["Unique Resource Linker","Uniform Resource Linker","Universal Resource Locator"],"question":"In computer networking, what do the initials URL stand for?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charlotte's Web","incorrectAnswers":["Animal Farm","Black Beauty","Watership Down"],"question":"Which book published in 1952 features an unusual friendship between a spider and a pig?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Joseph Fiennes","incorrectAnswers":["Tom Hiddleston","Benedict Cumberbatch","Hugh Grant"],"question":"Who played the title role in the movie Shakespeare In Love?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British rock band released the song 'Bicycle Race'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Blue with a yellow cross extending to the edges.","incorrectAnswers":["Red with a white crescent moon and star.","Three equal horizontal bands of red blue and orange.","Red with a black two headed eagle in the center."],"question":"What does the flag of Sweden look like?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Shuka","incorrectAnswers":["Kaftan","Thobe","Dashiki"],"question":"Which of these is a style of cloth used to make clothing by the Maasai people of East Africa?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"23","incorrectAnswers":["10","160","12"],"question":"How many pairs of chromosomes does the average person have?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Isosceles triangle","incorrectAnswers":["Equilateral triangle","Scalene triangle","Rectangle"],"question":"What is the name of a triangle with two sides of equal length?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Cameron Diaz","incorrectAnswers":["Penélope Cruz","Kristin Scott Thomas","Kirsten Dunst"],"question":"Which actress has played major roles in films including Gangs of New York and The Mask?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Myanmar","incorrectAnswers":["Bangladesh","Thailand","Cambodia"],"question":"Which of these countries borders People's Republic of China?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Meryl Streep","incorrectAnswers":["Cate Blanchett","Nicole Kidman","Natalie Portman"],"question":"Which actress has featured in films including The Deer Hunter and Out of Africa?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Barba non facit philosophum","incorrectAnswers":["Ad victoriam philos","Una philos non facit ver","Philosophum ad meliora"],"question":"Which of these Latin phrases means 'A beard doesn't make one a philosopher'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Royal disease","incorrectAnswers":["Laughing disease","Deadly disease","Happy disease"],"question":"As what is haemophilia also known?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Poland","incorrectAnswers":["Slovakia","Czech Republic","Hungary"],"question":"Warsaw is the capital of what country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ghosting","incorrectAnswers":["Dropping","Vanishing","Negging"],"question":"In modern slang, what is the term for abruptly cutting off all communication, especially with a romantic partner?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I am Groot.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Today, I consider myself the luckiest man on the face of the earth.\"","\"The stuff that dreams are made of.\"","\"I'll have what she's having.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Guardians of the Galaxy'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Clint Eastwood","incorrectAnswers":["Christopher Lee","James Dean","Marlon Brando"],"question":"Which actor starred in The Good, the Bad and the Ugly?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Henry II","incorrectAnswers":["Henry IV","Richard II","Richard I"],"question":"Who was the monarch of England during the time period 1154-1189?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"During WWII a Jewish waiter uses humor to protect his son from the realities of war.","incorrectAnswers":["Eddy has a week to pay back £500,000 after losing a poker game to a powerful local mobster.","The life of the lawyer who became the famed leader of the Indian revolts against the British rule.","A secretly ruthless woman insinuates herself into the lives of an aging actor and her circle of theater friends."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Life Is Beautiful?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A law enforcement agent pursues four replicants who have returned to Earth to find their creator.","incorrectAnswers":["A man houses over a thousand Tutsi refugees during their struggle against the Hutu militia.","When a serial killer murders key political figures, a vigilante is forced to intervene.","An insurance representative lets a housewife seduce him into a scheme of insurance fraud and murder."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Blade Runner?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Collage","incorrectAnswers":["Watercolor","Sculpture","Pointilism"],"question":"What is the word for a composition made of cut and pasted pieces of materials?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Isaac Newton","incorrectAnswers":["Daniel Defoe","Percy Bysshe Shelley","Walter Scott"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Opticks, or a Treatise of the Reflections, Refractions, Inflections and Colours of Light'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Anthony Eden","incorrectAnswers":["Clement Atlee","Margaret Thatcher","Tony Daniels"],"question":"Who succeeded Winston Churchill when he resigned in 1955?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Estonia","incorrectAnswers":["Finland","Macedonia","Bolivia"],"question":"In which country is vana tallinn a popular drink?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Sputnik","incorrectAnswers":["Endeavour","Landsat","Terra"],"question":"What was the name of the first artificial satellite to be launched into space?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Salvador Dali","incorrectAnswers":["Pablo Picasso","Andy Warhol","Damien Hirst"],"question":"Which artist produced a lobster telephone?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Ribbon pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Soup pasta","Stuffed pasta","Strand pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is linguine?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Chocolate ","incorrectAnswers":["Fudge","Cheese","Cream"],"question":"What Is Usually Served With A Fruit Fondue?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"England","incorrectAnswers":["Norway","Thailand","Mexico"],"question":"In which country is gin a popular drink?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bee Gees","incorrectAnswers":["ABBA","The Allman Brothers Band","Oasis"],"question":"Robin Gibb is one of the brothers who formed which band?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"M","incorrectAnswers":["Austin Powers: International Man of Mystery","Apocalypse Now","Home Alone"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Hans Beckert'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Moorish","incorrectAnswers":["Byzantine","Neoclassical","Gothic"],"question":"Which of the following is a style of Islamic architecture?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Black Widow","incorrectAnswers":["Brown Recluse","Daddy Longlegs","Tarantula"],"question":"Which venomous spider is recognized by its hourglass-shaped mark?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"23","incorrectAnswers":["10","2","12"],"question":"How Many Pairs of Chromosomes Does The Average Human Have?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"A boy's best friend is his mother.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"I'll have what she's having.\"","\"I love lamp.\"","\"Snap out of it!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Psycho'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"PETA","incorrectAnswers":["WWF","Greenpeace","The Humane Society"],"question":"What animal rights organization is known for its campaigns against animal testing and meat eating?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Mother","incorrectAnswers":["HAL","Colossus","Jarvis"],"question":"What is the nickname of the ship's computer in the 1979 film Alien?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Who","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Travis","Spandau Ballet"],"question":"Which English rock band released the album 'My Generation'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The heart","incorrectAnswers":["Knots","Japanese people","Poker"],"question":"What is Cardiology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Gustave Flaubert","incorrectAnswers":["Anatole France","Guy de Maupassant","Charles Perrault"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Salammbô'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Timothy Spall","incorrectAnswers":["Paul Newman","Tobey Maguire","Dennis Hopper"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including The King's Speech and Lemony Snicket's A Series of Unfortunate Events?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Pearl Harbour","incorrectAnswers":["D Day","The bombing of hiroshima","The Nazi invasion of France"],"question":"Which military attack took place on Dec. 7, 1941?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"I Am Not A Lawyer","incorrectAnswers":["I'm Anal","I Also Now Am Lonely","I'm Attractive, Not A Loser"],"question":"On internet chats, what do the letters 'IANAL' mean?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Asia ","incorrectAnswers":["North America","Europe","Africa"],"question":"Which Of The Worlds Continents Has The Highest Population?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Abraham Lincoln","incorrectAnswers":["George Washington","John F Kennedy","John Quincy Adams"],"question":"What United States president was in office during the civil war?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Stephen King","incorrectAnswers":["H. P. Lovecraft","Edgar Allan Poe","Jack Vance"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Insomnia'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Luxembourg","Denmark","Switzerland"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Kingdom of the Netherlands?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Maurice Gibb","incorrectAnswers":["Tom Jones","Paul McCartney","Brian Wilson"],"question":"Who did the singer Lulu marry in 1969?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"\"Annie\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"The Lion King\"","\"Phantom of the Opera\"","\"Les Miserables\""],"question":"What is the name of the ever-popular musical that features songs such as \"Little Girls\" and \"You Won't Be an Orphan for Long\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Luanda","incorrectAnswers":["Brazzaville","Nairobi","Dakar"],"question":"What is the capital of Angola?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Go","incorrectAnswers":["Scrabble","Chess","Clue"],"question":"What is the name of the classic game where players take turns placing black and white stones in an attempt to capture areas of the board?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Black Thursday","incorrectAnswers":["Dark Wednesday","Sorrowful Sunday","Miserable Monday"],"question":"How is the stockmarket collapse of the 24th October 1929 better known?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"South Korea & Japan","incorrectAnswers":["Brazil","South Africa","France"],"question":"Which country hosted the 2002 FIFA World Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Israel","incorrectAnswers":["Germany","Portugal","Chile"],"question":"Which country's flag can be described as 'White with a blue star centered between two equal horizontal blue bands'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Sir Francis Drake","incorrectAnswers":["Horatio Nelson","George Rodney","John Jervis"],"question":"Who Played Bowls Before Engaging The Spanish Armada?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"rocks and the conditions by which they form","incorrectAnswers":["demons","medicine relating to women, or of women in general","prehistoric metaphytes "],"question":"What is Petrology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Aphrodisiacs","incorrectAnswers":["Elixirs","Potions","Tonics"],"question":"Named after a Greek love goddess, which word is used for items that stimulate sexual desire?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Bugatti","incorrectAnswers":["Honda","Ferrari","Chevrolet"],"question":"Which car manufacturer makes the Veyron?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Sweden","incorrectAnswers":["Serbia","Senegal","Singapore"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.se' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Hotel Rwanda","incorrectAnswers":["The Terminator","Psycho","City of God"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A man houses over a thousand Tutsi refugees during their struggle against the Hutu militia.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Baku","incorrectAnswers":["Palikir","Valletta","Monrovia"],"question":"What is the capital city of Azerbaijan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Joker","incorrectAnswers":["1917","Mad Max: Fury Road","Grave of the Fireflies"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A stand-up comedian embarks on a downward spiral that leads to the creation of an iconic villain.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Apartheid","incorrectAnswers":["Apathy","Caste system","Feudalism"],"question":"What was the name of the system that kept Black and White people separated in South Africa?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Al dente ","incorrectAnswers":["Tartilli","Forte Benne","Parpa Delle"],"question":"Which Italian phrase is used to describe pasta cooked only until it offers a slight resistance when bitten?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Dead Sea","incorrectAnswers":["The Mediterranean Sea","The Philippine Sea","The South China Sea"],"question":"What is the saltiest sea in the world?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tripoli","incorrectAnswers":["Benghazi","Tehran","Rabat"],"question":"What is the capital of Libya? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Football","incorrectAnswers":["Rowing","Track and field","Gymnastics"],"question":"With which sport is Mia Hamm associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Johannesburg","incorrectAnswers":["Pretoria","Cape Town","Durban"],"question":"Which city is the most populated in South Africa?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kevin Spacey","incorrectAnswers":["Russell Crowe","Richard Farnsworth","Sean Penn"],"question":"Who won the 1999 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Lester Burnham in American Beauty?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dutch and Flemish Renaissance","incorrectAnswers":["Dadaism","Primitivism","post-impressionism"],"question":"The painting \"The Tower of Babel\" by Pieter Bruegel the Elder is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Precocious","incorrectAnswers":["Prodigious","Intelligent","Miraculous"],"question":"Which word is used to describe early achievement in children?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Taoism","incorrectAnswers":["Buddhism","Zoroastrianism","Hinduism"],"question":"What religion was founded by Lao-tzu ?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"California","incorrectAnswers":["New York","Florida"," Oklahoma"],"question":"In which US state did the \"Night Stalker\" serial killer commit his crime spree?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hilfiger","incorrectAnswers":["Lauren","Kors","Calvin"],"question":"What is the last name of the designer whose website is usa.tommy.com?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Sparta","incorrectAnswers":["Corinth","Mystras","Thebes"],"question":"Which Greek city-state, led by Lysander, defeated Athens in 404 B.C. and established the government of the 30 tyrants over it?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["Slovenia","Croatia","Liechtenstein"],"question":"Which of these countries borders San Marino?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"12 Years a Slave","incorrectAnswers":["American Hustle","Captain Phillips","Dallas Buyers Club"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2013?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Eight","incorrectAnswers":["Five","White","Seven"],"question":"What does the word 'ocho' mean in Spanish?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Arak","incorrectAnswers":["Sombai","Soju","Riga Black Balsam"],"question":"Which of these is a popular drink in Jordan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The Middle East","incorrectAnswers":["Japan","Cambodia","Scandinavia"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served Kibbeh?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The lives of guards on Death Row are affected by a man accused of child murder and rape.","incorrectAnswers":["An archaeologist is hired by the government to find the Ark of the Covenant.","Two men searching for work in 1920s Mexico convince an old prospector to help them mine for gold.","After a mathematician accepts secret work in cryptography, his life takes a turn for the nightmarish."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie The Green Mile?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Laurence Fishburne","incorrectAnswers":["Sean Connery","Gary Oldman","Donald Sutherland"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including The Matrix and Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Brideshead Revisited","incorrectAnswers":["Breakfast at Tiffany's","The Age of Innocence","An American Tragedy"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Sebastian Flyte'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bamako","incorrectAnswers":["Dakar","Accra","Kumasi"],"question":"What is the capital of Mali?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Welcome to the Black Parade\" by My Chemical Romance","incorrectAnswers":["\"Let's Go Crazy\" by Prince and The Revolution","\"Immigrant Song\" by Led Zeppelin","\"Rapper's Delight\" by Sugarhill Gang"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"When I was a young boy / My father took me into the city...\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"A Farewell to Arms","incorrectAnswers":["The Sun Also Rises","For Whom the Bell Tolls","The Old Man and the Sea"],"question":"Which Ernest Hemingway novel features Frederic Henry, a hero who serves as an ambulance driver during World War I?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Fipple","incorrectAnswers":["Smicker","Bibble","Firman"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'the mouthpiece of a recorder or similar wind instrument'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Oceania","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Europe","Asia"],"question":"The country of Nauru is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Amélie","incorrectAnswers":["Raging Bull","The Matrix","Warrior"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A girl with her own sense of justice decides to help those around her and discovers love.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Moscow","incorrectAnswers":["St Petersburg","Kazan","Vladivostok"],"question":"What is the capital city of Russia?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Japan","incorrectAnswers":["China","South Korea","Vietnam"],"question":"Tokyo is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Pablo Picasso","incorrectAnswers":["Sandro Botticelli","Peter Paul Rubens","Jacques-Louis David"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Les Demoiselles d’Avignon\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Football","incorrectAnswers":["Table tennis","Ice Hockey","Baseball"],"question":"With which sport is Jose Mourinho associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Walter Scott","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","J. R. R. Tolkien","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Heart of Midlothian'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Crust","incorrectAnswers":["Mantle","Core","Stoam"],"question":"What is the name of the solid outermost layer of the Earth?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jack Black","incorrectAnswers":["Ryan Reynolds","Hugh Jackman","Brian Cox"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including King Kong and Enemy of the State?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Bryan Singer","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed X-Men: Apocalypse?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bee Gees","incorrectAnswers":["Metallica","Culture Club","Dire Straits"],"question":"Which band did Maurice Gibb belong to?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Neptune","incorrectAnswers":["Uranus","Venus","Saturn"],"question":"Which planet is third in mass and eighth from the sun?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Tom Hanks","incorrectAnswers":["Morgan Freeman","Nigel Hawthorne","Paul Newman"],"question":"Who won the 1994 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Forrest Gump in Forrest Gump?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Little holes","incorrectAnswers":["Small thimbles","homemade","Corkscrews"],"question":"The pasta bucatini has what meaning in Italian?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A janitor has a gift for mathematics.","incorrectAnswers":["A tramp who has fallen in love with a blind flower girl saves money to help her medically.","After two male musicians witness a murder, they flee in an all-female band disguised as women.","Born in the stable next door to Christ, a man spends his life being mistaken for a messiah."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Good Will Hunting?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Australia","incorrectAnswers":["China","Italy","France"],"question":"In which country would you find the Sydney Opera House?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Sydney Harbour Bridge ","incorrectAnswers":["The Golden Gate Bridge","Tower Bridge","Brooklyn Bridge"],"question":"Which Famous City Bridge Is Known Locally As The Coathanger?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Who","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Travis","Spandau Ballet"],"question":"Which band includes 'Keith Moon'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Tanzania","incorrectAnswers":["Sri Lanka","India","Taiwan"],"question":"Swahili is a language spoken in which of these countries?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Dolomite","incorrectAnswers":["Gypsum","Baking Soda","Marsh Gas"],"question":"What is calcium magnesium carbonate commonly known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Jarrow March","incorrectAnswers":["The Swing Riots","Tolpuddle Martyrs","The Chartists"],"question":"What famous protest took place in Britain in 1936?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tee-ball","incorrectAnswers":["Korf-ball","Kinderball","Knuckleball"],"question":"What is a type of baseball designed for young players who are still developing their hitting skills?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Crusaders","incorrectAnswers":["The Zealots","The Infidels","The Righteous"],"question":"Who fought for the Holy Land between 1095 and 1291?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Galata Bridge","incorrectAnswers":["Bosphor Bridge","Istanbul Suspension Bridge","Topkaki Bridge"],"question":"Which Bridge Connects Europe With Asia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"the Sun","incorrectAnswers":["the age of the Earth","puzzles","neural diseases"],"question":"What is Heliology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Corned beef","incorrectAnswers":["Pastrami","Roast beef","Ham"],"question":"What type of meat is found in a Reuben sandwich?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Prince and the Pauper","incorrectAnswers":["The Boy in the Striped Pyjamas","The Name of the Rose","The Hobbit"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'I will set down a tale as it was told to me by one who had it of his father, which latter had it of HIS father, this last having in like manner had it of HIS father—and so on, back and still back, three hundred years and more, the fathers transmitting it to the sons and so preserving it.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Wuthering Heights","incorrectAnswers":["The Shining","The Phantom of the Opera","Coraline"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line '1801—I have just returned from a visit to my landlord—the solitary neighbour that I shall be troubled with.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Meryl Streep","incorrectAnswers":["Jane Alexander","Barbara Barrie","Candice Bergen"],"question":"Who won the 1979 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress for playing the role of Joanna Kramer in Kramer vs. Kramer?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"J. K. Rowling","incorrectAnswers":["Christopher Tolkien","Philip Pullman","C. S. Lewis"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Madonna","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Nicki Minaj","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which American singer and songwriter released the song 'Erotica'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Roger Moore","incorrectAnswers":["George Lazenby","Sean Connery","Timothy Dalton"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in Licence to Kill?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Bhutan","incorrectAnswers":["Turkey","Thailand","Bahrain"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served Ema Datshi?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Friedrich Schiller","incorrectAnswers":["Sebastian Brant","Agatha Christie","Rainer Maria Rilke"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Mary Stuart'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1936","incorrectAnswers":["1926","1916","1906"],"question":"In What Year Did The Spanish Civil War Begin?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Green","Gold","Orange"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Norway?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"With hard work, all things grow","incorrectAnswers":["The act done by me against my will is not my act","Seize the day","Honey, I'm home"],"question":"How does that Latin phrase 'Grandescunt aucta labore' translate into English?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Chevy Chase","incorrectAnswers":["Steve Martin","Tim Allen","Tom Hanks"],"question":"Who plays the lead role of the accident prone Clark Griswold in the 1989 'National Lampoon's Christmas Vacation''?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Martha's Vineyard","incorrectAnswers":["Long Island","Block Island","Cape Cod"],"question":"What is the name of the largest island in Massachusetts, famous for its lush scenery, beaches and celebrity sightings?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Oxter","incorrectAnswers":["Erf","Futz","Bumfuzzle"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'outdated word meaning “armpit”'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Micronesia","incorrectAnswers":["Israel","China","Malawi"],"question":"Palikir is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Gravlax","incorrectAnswers":["Kroppkakor","Smorgasbord","Falukorv"],"question":"What is the name of the Swedish specialty that consists of raw salmon cured in a salt-sugar-dill mixture?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Scamp","incorrectAnswers":["Sparky","Max","Bolt"],"question":"What is the name of the dog in the movie Lady and the Tramp?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Apple Bobbing","incorrectAnswers":["Trick or Treating","Jack o' Lanterns","Wearing Scary Outfits"],"question":"Which Halloween tradition originated from a custom to establish who would get married first?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Amazon","incorrectAnswers":["The Nile","The Danube","The Congo"],"question":"What river has the largest drainage basin?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Eddy Grant","incorrectAnswers":["Devo","Suzi Quatro","Nick Gilder"],"question":"'Electric Avenue' was a one hit wonder in 1983 by which artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Juarez","incorrectAnswers":["Tijuana","Nogales","Matamoros"],"question":"What is the name of El Paso's twin city on the Mexican side of the border?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Peenemunde","incorrectAnswers":["Hamburg","Lübeck","Rostock"],"question":"Which Baltic seaport was the German rocket centre during WWII?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Deciduous","incorrectAnswers":["Conifer","Gymnosperm","Evergreen"],"question":"From which type of tree do we get hardwood?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Writing a diary about her hide from the Germans in WW2","incorrectAnswers":["Winning a nobel prize for her research into radioactivity","Being the first woman to be elected to a head of state position","Being the first woman in space"],"question":"What was Anne Frank famous for?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Christopher Tolkien","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Gaiman","J. R. R. Tolkien","J. K. Rowling"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The War of the Jewels'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mars","incorrectAnswers":["Earth","Saturn","Venus"],"question":"The moons Deimos and Phobos orbit which planet in our solar system?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pamela Anderson","incorrectAnswers":["Jennifer Anniston","Kate Moss","Sharon Osborne"],"question":"Who did Tommy Lee of Motley Crue marry in the 90's? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Faroe Islands","incorrectAnswers":["Bulgaria","Bangladesh","Italy"],"question":"Which of these countries has blue on its flag?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The d in 'door'","incorrectAnswers":["The y in 'yellow'","The r in 'red'","The z in 'zoo'"],"question":"In phonetics, which of these is an example of a plosive sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"J. K. Rowling","incorrectAnswers":["Christopher Tolkien","Philip Pullman","C. S. Lewis"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pink Floyd","incorrectAnswers":["Black Sabbath","AC/DC","Fleetwood Mac"],"question":"Which group's first album was entitled 'Piper At the Gates Of Dawn''","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Who","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Travis","Spandau Ballet"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Pinball Wizard'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"California","incorrectAnswers":["Oregon","Florida","Idaho"],"question":"Which US state is home to the Sequoia National Forest?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Oceania","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Europe","Asia"],"question":"The country of Vanuatu is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Antimatter","incorrectAnswers":["Dark matter","Fluid matter","Matter waves"],"question":"What type of matter is a positron?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The Ramayana","incorrectAnswers":["The Upanishads","The Bhagavad Gita","The Puranas"],"question":"What is the name of the Hindu scripture that contains the story of Sita?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Gerald Ford","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Jefferson ","Donald J. Trump","Martin Van Buren "],"question":"Who was the 38th president of the USA, in term during the period 1974–1977?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Detroit","incorrectAnswers":["Cleveland","Chicago","Seattle"],"question":"Which city was Axel Foley a cop in before moving to Beverly Hills?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Adam Smith","incorrectAnswers":["Karl Marx","John Maynard Keynes","Milton Friedman"],"question":"\"Wealth of Nations\" was written by which economist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Philip Pullman","incorrectAnswers":["J. R. R. Tolkien","Christopher Tolkien","Neil Gaiman"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Northern Lights'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Halley's Comet","incorrectAnswers":["The Moon","Mars","Venus"],"question":"What was the 1986 Giotto probe designed to study?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"G.I. Joe","incorrectAnswers":["Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles","Scooby Doo","Transformers"],"question":"Which 80's cartoon ended with the phrase: 'And knowing is half the battle'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Get off my lawn.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"You know how I know that you’re gay?\"","\"Oh, no, it wasn't the airplanes. It was Beauty killed the Beast.\"","\"Sawyer, you're going out a youngster, but you've t to come back a star!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Gran Torino'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Morrisey","incorrectAnswers":["Forissey","Lorissey","Borissey"],"question":"What is the name of the lead singer for the Smiths?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"United Kingdom","incorrectAnswers":["Australia","Ireland","Canada"],"question":"In which country is the city of London?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Good King Wenceslas","incorrectAnswers":["Once in Royal David's City","Silent Night","Deck the Halls"],"question":"Which Christmas Carol tells the tale of a 10th century Duke of Bohemia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Scientist who discovered The Theory of Relativity.","incorrectAnswers":["Inventor of the telephone.","38th President of the US.","One of the principal interpreters of Confucianism."],"question":"Which of the following describes Albert Einstein?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Artist","incorrectAnswers":["The Descendants","Extremely Loud & Incredibly Close","The Help"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2011?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Resident Evil","incorrectAnswers":["Left 4 Dead","Dead Space","The Last of Us"],"question":"What horror video game involves surviving environments infested with zombies, and was later adapted into a movie starring Milla Jovovich?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Chestnuts","incorrectAnswers":["Onions","Turkey","Marshmallows"],"question":"According to 'A Christmas Song'', what would you find roasting over an open fire?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Russell Crowe","incorrectAnswers":["Seth Rogen","John Wayne","Ron Perlman"],"question":"Which actor has starred in both Gladiator and A Beautiful Mind?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Offspring","incorrectAnswers":["Styx","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which punk band from the United States released the studio album 'Rise and Fall, Rage and Grace'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"24","incorrectAnswers":["16","20","12"],"question":"How Many Draughts Are On The Board At The Start Of A Game?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Lebanon","incorrectAnswers":["Jordan","Israel","Cyprus"],"question":"___________ is the only country in the Middle East that does not have a desert.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Big Bang Theory","incorrectAnswers":["General Relativity","String Theory","Quantum Theory"],"question":"What is the name of the scientific theory that states that the universe began with a singularity?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Agra","incorrectAnswers":["Mumbai","Kolkata","Chennai"],"question":"In Which Indian City Is The Taj Mahal","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kim Basinger","incorrectAnswers":["Sally Hawkins","Lucy Lawless","Jacqueline Bisset"],"question":"Which actress has starred in films including Batman and L.A. Confidential?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Muse","incorrectAnswers":["Tears for Fears","Bullet For My Valentine","Enter Shikari"],"question":"Which English rock band released the album 'The Resistance'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bob Dylan","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Young","Eric Clapton","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which American musician released the song 'Hurricane'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Peter Finch","incorrectAnswers":["Jaye Davidson","Malcolm McDowell","Jeff Bridges"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Howard Beale in Network?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Dubrovnik","incorrectAnswers":["Lisbon","Geneva","Amsterdam"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Croatia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Maseru","incorrectAnswers":["Tashkent","Praia","Bratislava"],"question":"What is the capital city of Lesotho?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The F1 Grand Prix","incorrectAnswers":["The FIFA World Cup","The Africa Cup of Nations","The Hopman Cup"],"question":"Which of these is a Motorsports competition?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Valkyrie","incorrectAnswers":["Dunkirk","Saving Private Ryan","Schindler's List"],"question":"What is the name of the 2008 WWII film that had the tagline \"Many saw evil. They dared to stop it\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"North America","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Dominica is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Peru","incorrectAnswers":["Jamaica","North Macedonia","Colombia"],"question":"Which of these countries has white on its flag?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Daft Punk","incorrectAnswers":["Gong","Indochine","Nouvelle Vague"],"question":"Which French electronica duo released the song 'One More Time'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Rat","incorrectAnswers":["Squirrel","Rabbit","Shrew"],"question":"A __________ can squeeze through an opening no larger than a dime?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Dickens","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Joseph Conrad","Henryk Sienkiewicz"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Mystery of Edwin Drood'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"proper names","incorrectAnswers":["prehistoric metaphytes ","prehistoric metazoans ","interactions between organisms and geomorphological processes"],"question":"What is Onomatology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Honey ","incorrectAnswers":["Butter","Almond","Lemon"],"question":"From what is mead made?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Saturn","incorrectAnswers":["Neptune","Jupiter","Earth"],"question":"Name the second largest planet in the solar system.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Faces","incorrectAnswers":["The Rolling Stones","Deep Purple","Oasis"],"question":"Which band was Rod Stewart a member of before going solo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Guy de Maupassant","incorrectAnswers":["François-René de Chateaubriand","Anatole France","Albert Camus"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Au soleil'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red with a yellow sun having eight broadening rays extending to the edges.","incorrectAnswers":["Two equal horizontal bands of red and white.","Blue with a red cross outlined in white extending to the edges.","White with a blue star centered between two equal horizontal blue bands"],"question":"What does the flag of North Macedonia look like?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hans Christian Andersen","incorrectAnswers":["Beatrix Potter","Søren Kierkegaard","Oscar Wilde"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Little Mermaid'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of The Gambia is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sarah Jessica Parker","incorrectAnswers":["Audrey Hepburn","Sally Hawkins","Lucy Lawless"],"question":"Which actress has starred in both Sex and the City and Ed Wood?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Football","incorrectAnswers":["Snooker","Cricket","Motor racing"],"question":"With which sport is Cristiano Ronaldo associated?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"12","incorrectAnswers":["10","13","11"],"question":"Introduced in 46 BC by Julius Caesar, how many months was the Julian calendar divided into?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Thor","incorrectAnswers":["Loki","Odin","Freyja"],"question":"Which Norse god known for his great strength was a protector of peasants and farmers?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red with a yellow star in the center.","incorrectAnswers":["Blue with a yellow cross extending to the edges.","White with a large red disk in the center.","Three equal vertical bands of blue gold and red."],"question":"What does the flag of Vietnam look like?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Mario Puzo","incorrectAnswers":["Edgar Allan Poe","Stephen King","Dan Brown"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Godfather'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Nirvana","incorrectAnswers":["The Isley Brothers","Van Halen","Devo"],"question":"The song 'Smells Like Teen Spirit' had a well-known cover by Tori Amos, but who recorded the original?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Madagascar","incorrectAnswers":["Germany","Myanmar","Latvia"],"question":"Antananarivo is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Machu Picchu","incorrectAnswers":["Angkor Wat","Petra","Chichen Itza"],"question":"Which lost city can you see while hiking the Inca trail from Cuzco?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Gary Oldman","incorrectAnswers":["James Franco","George Clooney","Laurence Fishburne"],"question":"Which actor has starred in both Harry Potter and Batman Begins?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Philadelphia Union","incorrectAnswers":["Philadelphia Indians","Philadelphia Ravens","Philadelphia Reds"],"question":"Which of these is a soccer team based in Philadelphia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Indian Ocean","incorrectAnswers":["Pacific Ocean","Atlantic Ocean","Mediterranean Sea"],"question":"In which body of water is Christmas Island?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Sudan","incorrectAnswers":["Ecuador","Nepal","Malaysia"],"question":"Khartoum is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hertz","incorrectAnswers":["Joule","Watt","Pascal"],"question":"What are the units of measurement for Frequency?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"0","incorrectAnswers":["3","1","6"],"question":"How many moons does Mercury have?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Calcium carbonate","incorrectAnswers":["Deuterium Oxide","Calcium magnesium carbonate","Sodium bicarbonate"],"question":"What chemical compound makes limestone?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Athens","incorrectAnswers":["Jerusalem","Moscow","Venice"],"question":"In which city would you find the Acropolis?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Anemia","incorrectAnswers":["Diabetes","Cancer","Arthritis"],"question":"What disease may be diagnosed by checking Vitamin B12 levels and is characterized by a lack of red blood cells?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"W. K. Clifford","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hobbes","Ludwig Wittgenstein","Epictetus"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'It is wrong always, everywhere and for everyone, to believe anything upon insufficient evidence'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ireland","incorrectAnswers":["Scotland","Wales","France"],"question":"Which country is associated with a harp, which is featured on its national emblem?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Three Times","incorrectAnswers":["Once","No Times","Five Times"],"question":"How many times did Peter deny Jesus?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"160","incorrectAnswers":["0","50","300"],"question":"Approximately how many children did pharaoh Ramses II father?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Diagonally","incorrectAnswers":["Vertically","Horizontally","Backwards"],"question":"The king crab walks __________","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1989","incorrectAnswers":["1980","1985","1994"],"question":"In which year did the Berlin Wall fall?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Lot","incorrectAnswers":["Boys","Witches","Game"],"question":"Stephen King's: \"Salem's _________\".","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"DNA","incorrectAnswers":["GCI","ATP","COD"],"question":"What is the abbreviation for the polymer that carries genetic instructions for living cells?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Roman Polanski","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed The Pianist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Autobahn","incorrectAnswers":["Bundestrasse","Reichstag","Schwartzkopf"],"question":"What word is used for Germany's main highways?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1967","incorrectAnswers":["1922","1869","1894"],"question":"In which year did the Six-Day War take place?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Spiced Ham ","incorrectAnswers":["Special Made Artifial Meat","Superior Manufactured Artificial Meat","Special Ham"],"question":"What Is 'SPAM' Short For?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Motörhead","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Motley Crüe"],"question":"Which band was founded by Lemmy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Not my tempo.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Today, I consider myself the luckiest man on the face of the earth.\"","\"Just keep swimming.\"","\"You shall not pass!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Whiplash'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Virgin","incorrectAnswers":["Unrefined","Pure","Organic"],"question":"What grade of olive oil comes only from mechanically pressed olives with no chemical treatment?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Crying Game","incorrectAnswers":["Sunset Boulevard","Bringing Up Baby","A Clockwork Orange"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Dil'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The art using make-up","incorrectAnswers":["Winemaking","The Sumerians","The cosmos"],"question":"What is Cosmetology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Mistletoe","incorrectAnswers":["Holly","Mimosa","Lavender"],"question":"At Christmas, it is customary to exchange kisses beneath a sprig of which plant?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A sedge","incorrectAnswers":["A sloth","A yoke","An unkindness"],"question":"What is the word for a group of herons?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Yak","incorrectAnswers":["Goat","Lama","Bison"],"question":"Which Small Breed Of Cattle Is Found Wile In The Tibetan Plateu , North Of The Himalayas","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Grand prix","incorrectAnswers":["Bon appétit","Vive la France","C'est la vie"],"question":"What is the French term for a big prize?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Spinal cord","incorrectAnswers":["Vagus nerve","Ribcage","Trachea"],"question":"In the human body, what is the name of the structure that runs down the middle of the back?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Baz Luhrmann","incorrectAnswers":["Darren Aronofsky","Christopher Nolan","Steven Spielberg"],"question":"Which director of the film \"Moulin Rouge!\" brought his hit production of \"La boheme\" to Broadway in 2002?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Mini","incorrectAnswers":["Beetle","Porsche 911","E-Type"],"question":"Which iconic car did Austin And Morris launch in 1959?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Million Dollar Baby","incorrectAnswers":["The Aviator","Finding Neverland","Ray"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2004?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Joey","incorrectAnswers":["Ross","Chandler","Buster"],"question":"What is the name of the character played by Matt LeBlanc on 'Friends'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The 1950s","incorrectAnswers":["The 1960s","The 1970s","The 1980s"],"question":"Which decade is known for literary works such as \"The Crucible\" and \"On the Road\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Marquis de Sade","incorrectAnswers":["Nikolai Gogol","J. R. R. Tolkien","Virginia Woolf"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The 120 Days of Sodom'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Monopoly","incorrectAnswers":["Scrabble","Chess","Risk"],"question":"Which board game can you get in a French language edition, with properties like Place du Parc and Promenade?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1927","incorrectAnswers":["1918","1936","1945"],"question":"When was the first movie with sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Zoe Saldana","incorrectAnswers":["Catherine Deneuve","Audrey Hepburn","Rachel Weisz"],"question":"Which actress has starred in films including Avengers: Endgame and Avatar?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Slipknot","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which heavy metal band from the United States released the studio album 'Iowa'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A young boy, left without attention, delves into a life of petty crime.","incorrectAnswers":["A sole survivor tells of the twisty events leading up to a horrific gun battle on a boat.","The final secretary for Adolf Hitler tells of the Nazi dictator's final days.","An aspiring musician enters the Land of the Dead to find his great-great-grandfather."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie The 400 Blows?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["Lithuania","Sweden","Serbia"],"question":"Milan is a city in which country?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Ming","incorrectAnswers":["Tang","Qing","Wu"],"question":"Which dynasty ruled China from 1368- to 1644?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Athletics","incorrectAnswers":["Boxing","Motor racing","Rowing"],"question":"With which sport is Kenenisa Bekele associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The blue whale","incorrectAnswers":["The elephant","The giraffe","The hippopotamus"],"question":"What is the largest mammal in the world?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Share moments. Share life.","incorrectAnswers":["Your vision. Our future.","At the heart of the image","See what we mean"],"question":"What is the marketing slogan of Kodak?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Heights","incorrectAnswers":["Sir Mix-A-Lot","House of Pain","Men Without Hats"],"question":"Who had a hit in 1992 with How Do You Talk to an Angel??","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hippie","incorrectAnswers":["Grunge","Gothic","Preppy"],"question":"What is the name of the fashion trend popularized in the 1960s that involves wearing bright colors and psychedelic patterns?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A man becomes concerned for his Jewish workforce after witnessing their persecution by the Nazis.","incorrectAnswers":["In order to power the city, beasts have to scare children so that they scream.","A girl wanders into a world ruled by gods, witches, and spirits, where humans are changed into beasts.","King Arthur and his Knights embark on a search for a religious relic."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Schindler's List?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Cm","incorrectAnswers":["C","Cu","Cr"],"question":"What is the chemical symbol for curium?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Elton John","incorrectAnswers":["David Bowie","John Lennon","Tom Jones"],"question":"Who Was The Star Behind Rocket Records?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Beijing","incorrectAnswers":["Hong Kong","Shanghai","Chengdu"],"question":"What is the capital of China?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"It Takes Two","incorrectAnswers":["I Touch Myself","How Bizarre","Whip It"],"question":"What song did Rob Base & DJ E-Z Rock have a hit with in 1988?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hit and run","incorrectAnswers":["Crush and leave","Drive and go","Smack and flee"],"question":"What is the term used to describe an accident in which the driver flees the scene?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Attila the Huns","incorrectAnswers":["Vlad the Impaler","Ivan the Terrible","Xerxes"],"question":"Which ancient ruler was known as the \"Scourge of God\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Germany","incorrectAnswers":["Luxembourg","Denmark","Switzerland"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Kingdom of the Netherlands?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Spice Girls","incorrectAnswers":["Girls Aloud","All Saints","B*Witched"],"question":"Which 90's girl group was Victoria Beckham a member of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Deer Hunter","incorrectAnswers":["Coming Home","Heaven Can Wait","Midnight Express"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1978?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"US Dollar","incorrectAnswers":["Euro","Japanese Yen","British Pound"],"question":"What is the most traded currency in the world?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"A Pea ","incorrectAnswers":["A Squash","A mushroom","A root"],"question":"What Type Of Vegetable Is A Marrow Fat?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Laughing my ass off","incorrectAnswers":["Letting me air out","Loving my ambitious outlook","Leading me and objecting"],"question":"If someone typed the letters 'LMAO' in a message, what would they mean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Sodium hydroxide","incorrectAnswers":["Sodium tetraborate decahydrate","Silicon dioxide","Deuterium oxide"],"question":"What chemical has the formula NaOH?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Russia","incorrectAnswers":["Bangladesh","Thailand","Cambodia"],"question":"Which of these countries borders People's Republic of China?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Law of Conservation of Energy","incorrectAnswers":["Law of Universal Gravitation","Law of Thermodynamics","Law of the Lever"],"question":"What is the name of the physical law that states that energy is neither created or destroyed?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Color Field Painting","incorrectAnswers":["Foreshortening","Gestural Painting","Canvas Filling"],"question":"Which technique in abstract painting developed in the 1950's focuses on the effects of large areas of color having a minimum of surface detail?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Polka","incorrectAnswers":["Bolka","Molka","Tolka"],"question":"What word could refer to a dance or a dot?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Turkic","Austronesian","Dravidian"],"question":"The language 'Iranian Persian' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Mongols","incorrectAnswers":["The Huns","The Parthians","The Greeks"],"question":"Which people were led by Genghis Khan?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Émile Zola","incorrectAnswers":["Alphonse Daudet","Anatole France","Charles Dickens"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Thérèse Raquin'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Jawaharlal Nehru","incorrectAnswers":["Mahatma Gandhi","Indira Gandhi","Subhas Chandra Bose"],"question":"Who was the first Prime Minister of India?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Atlanta Falcons","incorrectAnswers":["Atlanta Dynamo","Atlanta Marlins","Atlanta Rockets"],"question":"Which of these is an American Football team based in Atlanta?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Lady Gaga","incorrectAnswers":["Hikaru Utada","Drake","Madonna"],"question":"Which American singer, songwriter, and actress released the song 'G.U.Y.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"E. B. White","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Jordan","Philip K. Dick","Isabel Allende"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Charlotte's Web'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Joe Dimaggio","incorrectAnswers":["Jesse Jackson","Michael Jordan","Mohammed Ali"],"question":"Which sportsman is mentioned in the Simon & Garfunkel song Mrs Robinson?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Confirmed the theory that Earth revolves around The Sun.","incorrectAnswers":["Roman ruler who overthrew Caesar Augustus","Physicist who made major discoveries in quantum theory.","38th President of the US."],"question":"Which of the following describes Galileo Galilei?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tej","incorrectAnswers":["Horilka","Canelazo","Sangria"],"question":"Which of these is a popular drink in Ethiopia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bob Dylan","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Young","Eric Clapton","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which American musician released the song 'Mr. Tambourine Man'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn","incorrectAnswers":["Henryk Sienkiewicz","Oscar Wilde","Ivan Turgenev"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Gulag Archipelago'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Simon & Garfunkel","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American music duo released the song 'Mrs. Robinson'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Doe","incorrectAnswers":["A Leopardess","A Vixen","A Ewe"],"question":"What is a female mouse known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sean Connery","incorrectAnswers":["George Lazenby","Roger Moore","Pierce Brosnan"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in Goldfinger?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Werner Heisenberg","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen Hawking","Gregor Mendel","Leonhard Euler"],"question":"Which influential theoretical physicist was one of the pioneers of Quantum mechanics?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Ankylosaurus","incorrectAnswers":["Triceratops","Stegosaurus","Parasaurolophus"],"question":"What is the name of the dinosaur with a club-like tail?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Crayfish","incorrectAnswers":["Earth materials","Blood","The night sky"],"question":"What is Astacology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Eagles","incorrectAnswers":["Led Zeppelin","Black Sabbath","Aerosmith"],"question":"'Witchy Woman' was a hit for which rock group in the 1970's?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"I don't care","incorrectAnswers":["Interdependent carers","In da crew","I'm doing crap"],"question":"If someone typed the letters 'IDC' in a message, what would they mean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Laika the Dog","incorrectAnswers":["Churley the Chimpanzee","Feefo the Cat","Monty the Rat"],"question":"Who Was The First Animal In Space?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Beetles","incorrectAnswers":["The Shroud of Turin","Angels","The upper atmosphere"],"question":"What is Coleopterology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Roll","incorrectAnswers":["Dough","Pull","Wrap"],"question":"Who is Mega Man's sister?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Central Intelligence Agency","incorrectAnswers":["Federal Bureau of Investigation","Internal Revenue Service","National Aeronautics and Space Administration"],"question":"What is the name of the United States government organization established in 1947 with headquarters in Langley, Virginia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Swipe right","incorrectAnswers":["Like it","Thumbs up","Heart it"],"question":"What is the two-word term that the Tinder app has popularized, meaning to accept or approve of something?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Othello","incorrectAnswers":["Romeo","Juliet","Mercutio"],"question":"Which of the following characters is not a part of Shakespeare's 'Romeo and Juliet'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"It is used in fertilizers, rocket propellants and fireworks.","incorrectAnswers":["It is used in baking to stabilize egg whites.","It is used as an ingredient in the production of glass, bricks, and ceramics.","It is a poisonous gas."],"question":"What is the chemical potassium nitrate often used for?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Madrid","incorrectAnswers":["San Marino","Barcelona","Seville"],"question":"What is the capital city of Spain?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"J. R. R. Tolkien","incorrectAnswers":["G. K. Chesterton","Philip Pullman","C. S. Lewis"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Hobbit'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Crete ","incorrectAnswers":["Corfu","Mykonos","Rhodes"],"question":"Which Is The Largest Of The Greek Islands?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'I Feel Fine'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Basketball","incorrectAnswers":["Track and field","Motor racing","Boxing"],"question":"With which sport is Magic Johnson associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Humpty Dumpty","incorrectAnswers":["Hey Diddle Diddle","Mary Had a Little Lamb","Baa Baa Black Sheep"],"question":"What nursery rhyme is about a man who falls off a wall?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ben Kingsley","incorrectAnswers":["Kiefer Sutherland","Michael Douglas","Josh Brolin"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Iron Man 3 and Schindler's List?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Thailand","incorrectAnswers":["China","Saudi Arabia","Turkey"],"question":"What country was formerly known as Siam?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"feces","incorrectAnswers":["underground water","the field of medicine that deals with the skin","drug dosage"],"question":"What is Scatology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"butterflies and moths","incorrectAnswers":["animal diseases","the effect of light on chemicals","the historical study of languages"],"question":"What is Lepidopterology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The Beginning","incorrectAnswers":["The End","Between Courses","With A Soup"],"question":" At which stage of a meal would you have an hors d'oeuvre?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Saint Kitts and Nevis","incorrectAnswers":["Andorra","Liberia","Switzerland"],"question":"Basseterre is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Britannia","incorrectAnswers":["Albion","Roma","Britanica"],"question":"What was the name the Romans gave to Great Britain?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Shells and molluscs","incorrectAnswers":["The Weather","The origin and spread of diseases","Sex"],"question":"What is conchology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Joaquin Phoenix","incorrectAnswers":["Peter O'Toole","Roger Moore","Alan Cumming"],"question":"Which actor has played iconic roles in both Gladiator and Joker?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Alicia Vikander","incorrectAnswers":["Jennifer Jason Leigh","Rooney Mara","Rachel McAdams"],"question":"Who won the 2015 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress for playing the role of Gerda in The Danish Girl?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Cleopatra","incorrectAnswers":["Hatsheput","Nefertiti","Nitocris"],"question":"Who Was Ptolemy Dionysius Related To As Both Brother And Husband?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Kimono","incorrectAnswers":["Cheongsam","Sari","Hijab"],"question":"What is the Asian-style robe that is often used as a dressing gown?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"James Joyce","incorrectAnswers":["Samuel Beckett","Oscar Wilde","Jonathan Swift"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Finnegans Wake'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Prada","incorrectAnswers":["Armani","Gucci","Versace"],"question":"What is the last name of the Italian fashion designer Miuccia, who works for her family's fashion house & founded its sister line Miu Miu?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Venus","incorrectAnswers":["Jupiter","Mercury","Mars"],"question":"Which is the hottest planet in the Solar System?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Cells","incorrectAnswers":["Genetics","War","Hair"],"question":"What is Cytology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Farrow","incorrectAnswers":["A Larva","A Caterpillar","A Codling"],"question":"A young hog is known as what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Beijing","incorrectAnswers":["Hong Kong","Shanghai","Guangzhou"],"question":"What Is The Capital Of China?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Madonna","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Nicki Minaj","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which American singer released the album 'Confessions on a Dance Floor'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Play it, Sam. Play 'As Time goes By.'\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"That’s a bingo!\"","\"Look at me. I’m the captain now.\"","\"Who's on first.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Casablanca'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Gerard Butler","incorrectAnswers":["Hugh Jackman","Robert Redford","Jim Carrey"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including 300 and James Bond: Tomorrow Never Dies?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Feeder","The Clash","Pink Floyd"],"question":"Which British rock band released the single 'Another One Bites the Dust'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Salem","incorrectAnswers":["Greensboro","Alexandria","Wilmington"],"question":"In Sabrina The Teenage Witch What Is The Name Of Sabrina's Cat?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Et tu, Brute?","incorrectAnswers":["Veni, Vidi, Vici.","Carpe Diem!","Memento Mori?"],"question":"What are commonly believed to be the last words of Julius Caesar?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The twenty first","incorrectAnswers":["The third","The fifth","The eighteith"],"question":"What amendment to the u.s. constitution ended prohibition","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Cartilage","incorrectAnswers":["Tendon","Ligament","Muscle"],"question":"What part of the body, often referred to as 'gristle', is important for the formation of bones?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Brass","incorrectAnswers":["Woodwind","Percussion","Stringed"],"question":"What type of instrument is a bugle?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"2015","incorrectAnswers":["2000","1993","2004"],"question":"In which year was the creation of the first artificial heart?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Neptunium","incorrectAnswers":["Francium","Plutonium","Americium"],"question":"What is the atomic number of the first transuranium element?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Friedrich Schiller","incorrectAnswers":["Sebastian Brant","Agatha Christie","Rainer Maria Rilke"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Intrigue and Love'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Peanuts","incorrectAnswers":["Lentils","Black beans","Chickpeas"],"question":"Which of these is a major food allergen?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Profiterole","incorrectAnswers":["Strudel","Kringle","Cannoli"],"question":"Which of these desserts is a ball of choux pastry filled with cream?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Alice Munro","incorrectAnswers":["Ivan Turgenev","E. T. A. Hoffmann","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Family Furnishings: Selected Stories 1995-2014'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Cria","incorrectAnswers":["A Baby","A Lamb","An Infant"],"question":"What would you call a baby llama?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Vinegar","incorrectAnswers":["Aspirin","Lemon Juice","Soap"],"question":"Acetic Acid Is More Commonly Known As What?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Enrico Fermi","incorrectAnswers":["Joseph Lister","Nicolaus Copernicus","Constantine the Great"],"question":"Which influential physicist created the first nuclear reactor?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"James Abbott McNeill Whistler","incorrectAnswers":["‎‎Edvard Munch","‎Pablo Picasso","Diego Velázquez"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Whistler’s Mother\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Police","incorrectAnswers":["The Rolling Stones","U2","Ultravox"],"question":"Which band had Sting as its lead singer?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Afroasiatic","incorrectAnswers":["Sino-Tibetan","Austronesian","Turkic"],"question":"The language 'South Levantine Arabic' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Nellie Melba","incorrectAnswers":["Esmerelda Tiramisu","Fannie Brulée","Bridget Treacle"],"question":"Which Opera Singer had a dessert named after her?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Nonagon","incorrectAnswers":["Octagon","Hexagon","Septagon"],"question":"What is the name of a shape with nine sides?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Let","incorrectAnswers":["Dus","Par","See"],"question":"What 3 Letter Word It The Name Given To A Replayed Point In Tennis?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Smile","incorrectAnswers":["Grin","Laugh","Cry"],"question":"Which legendary Beach boys album was never completed?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Sally Ride","incorrectAnswers":["Joan Jett","Mary Winn","Ella Davis"],"question":"Who was the first female American astronaut?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas","incorrectAnswers":["On the Road","Blood Meridian","Catch-22"],"question":"Which Hunter S. Thompson book involves a wild journey through the desert and a series of autobiographical stories?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Susan Sarandon","incorrectAnswers":["Kate Winslet","Helen Mirren","Maggie Smith"],"question":"Which actress has starred in in films including The Rocky Horror Picture Show and Fame?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Friedrich Engels","incorrectAnswers":["Michael Ende","Erich Maria Remarque","Karl May"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Communist Manifesto'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Buckingham Palace","incorrectAnswers":["Windsor Castle","Kensington Palace","St. James's Palace"],"question":"What is the name of the London residence of the British monarch?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Usual Suspects","incorrectAnswers":["The Shining","Ghost","The Adventures of Robin Hood"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Roger \"Verbal\" Kint'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1910","incorrectAnswers":["1810","1710","2010"],"question":"In which year did the Mexican Revolution begin?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Comfortably Numb\" by Pink Floyd","incorrectAnswers":["\"Rapper's Delight\" by Sugarhill Gang","\"Welcome to the Black Parade\" by My Chemical Romance","\"Baby Got Back\" by Sir Mix-a-Lot"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Hello? Is there anybody in there?\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"John Locke","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hobbes","Baruch Spinoza","Jean-Jacques Rousseau"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'No man's knowledge here can go beyond his experience'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"U2","incorrectAnswers":["Public Image Ltd.","The Script","The Cure"],"question":"Which Irish rock band released the song 'Walk On'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1939","incorrectAnswers":["1915","1923","1931"],"question":"In which year was The Wizard of Oz released?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Golf","incorrectAnswers":["Table tennis","Swimming","Rowing"],"question":"With which sport is Tiger Woods associated?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Black Widow","incorrectAnswers":["Tarantula","Jumping Spider","Crab Spider"],"question":"Which Spider Devours Its Partner After Mating?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bangalore","incorrectAnswers":["Christchurch","Beijing","Wellington"],"question":"Which of these cities is in India?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Fish","incorrectAnswers":["Meat","Vegetables","Fruit"],"question":"What is the English translation of the French word \"poisson\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Karl Marx","incorrectAnswers":["Epictetus","Friedrich Nietzsche","Martin Heidegger"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Philosophers have hitherto only interpreted the world in various ways; the point, however, is to change it'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"George Orwell","incorrectAnswers":["Joseph Conrad","Virginia Woolf","Charles Dickens"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Animal Farm'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Nomadland","incorrectAnswers":["The Father","Judas and the Black Messiah","Mank"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2020?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Mannerism","incorrectAnswers":["Italian Renaissance","Baroque","Dutch and Flemish Renaissance"],"question":"The painting \"View of Toledo\" by El Greco is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pink Floyd","incorrectAnswers":["Wings","Rudimental","The Alan Parsons Project"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Comfortably Numb'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Toulouse","incorrectAnswers":["Barcelona","Copenhagen","Amsterdam"],"question":"Which of these cities is in France?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Atmospheric dust and its effects","incorrectAnswers":["Life","Human culture","Dogs"],"question":"What is Coniology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Vatican City","incorrectAnswers":["Monaco","Nauru","San Marino"],"question":"What is the smallest country in the world?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Seven","incorrectAnswers":["Yellow","White","Black"],"question":"In Spanish, what is the meaning of the word 'siete'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Metallica","incorrectAnswers":["Alice Cooper","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American heavy metal band released the song 'Master of Puppets'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Oak Tree","incorrectAnswers":["Fir Tree","Maple Tree","Elm Tree"],"question":"What type of tree is known for its large, dark green leaves?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Fourteenth","incorrectAnswers":["Twentieth","Tenth","Seventh"],"question":"In which century was The Black Death?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"measurement","incorrectAnswers":["the relationship of biological or other phenomena to their locations","spiders and their kind","wounds and injuries caused by accidents or assaults and their surgical treatment and repair"],"question":"What is Metrology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jack Vance","incorrectAnswers":["H. P. Lovecraft","Edgar Rice Burroughs","Ursula K. Le Guin"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Planet of Adventure'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Carrie Underwood","incorrectAnswers":["Taylor Swift","Miranda Lambert","Faith Hill"],"question":"Which female country singer had hits such as 'Jesus, Take the Wheel' and 'Some Hearts,' and also won 'American Idol'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Central America","Central Asia","Southeast Asia"],"question":"From which part of the world does mango originate?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Cuba","incorrectAnswers":["Dominican Republic","Nicaragua","Honduras"],"question":"From which country do pre-embargo 1950s Romeo y Julietas, a type of cigar, sell for as much as $400 each?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Plant nutrition in relation to soil conditions","incorrectAnswers":["Existence","Dreams","Emetics"],"question":"What is Agrobiology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"L'chaim","incorrectAnswers":["Shalom","Mazel tov","Todah rabah"],"question":"What is the Hebrew phrase that is used as a toast to life or to good health?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ridley Scott","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Alien?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Metallica","incorrectAnswers":["Alice Cooper","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American heavy metal band released the studio album 'Master of Puppets'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Neptune","incorrectAnswers":["Jupiter","Uranus","Saturn"],"question":"Which planet has the longest orbit around the sun?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Escort","incorrectAnswers":["Beetle","Passat","Model S"],"question":"Which of these is a model of car made by Ford?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Operation Bagration","incorrectAnswers":["Operation Barbarossa","Operation Overlord","Operation Market Garden"],"question":"What was the name of the Soviet Union's counter-attack on Germany in 1944?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cuba ","incorrectAnswers":["Barbados","Jamaica","Trinidad"],"question":"Which Is The Largest Island In The Caribbean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Master and Commander","incorrectAnswers":["Pirates of the Caribbean","The Last Samurai","Gladiator"],"question":"In which period film did Billy Boyd serve as Russell Crowe's coxswain?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Bonnie and Clyde","incorrectAnswers":["The French Connection","Dirty Harry","The Godfather"],"question":"Which crime film from 1967 features Gene Hackman as Buck Barrow?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The United Nations","incorrectAnswers":["The European Union","The League of Nations","Interpol"],"question":"Which major international organization was created in 1945?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hamlet","incorrectAnswers":["Macbeth","King Lear","Othello"],"question":"Which 5-act Shakespearean tragedy was partially based on a history of Denmark written by Saxo Grammaticus?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cuba","incorrectAnswers":["Mexico","Ecuador","Argentina"],"question":"With which country is Fidel Castro associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Crime","incorrectAnswers":["Human growth","Spiders","The color red"],"question":"What is criminology the study of?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"University of Michigan","incorrectAnswers":["Ohio State University","University of Notre Dame","Harvard University"],"question":"In which university was Gerald Ford voted MVP of the football team in 1934?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"L'Anse aux Meadows","incorrectAnswers":["Quebec","Hedgesville","Iceland"],"question":"What was the name of the Viking settlement that was established in Newfoundland, Canada?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Epicurus","incorrectAnswers":["Jean-Paul Sartre","Niccolo Machiavelli","Bertrand Russell"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'The greater the difficulty, the more glory in surmounting it'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Alchemists","incorrectAnswers":["Hussars","Chandlers","Smelters"],"question":"What type of people were obsessed with turning ordinary metals into gold in the Middle Ages?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Azan","incorrectAnswers":["Adhan","Quran","Iqama"],"question":"What is the name of the Islamic call to prayer?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Tell 'em to go out there with all they got and win just one for the Gipper.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"My precious.\"","\"Houston, we have a problem.\"","\"No wire hangers, ever!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Knute Rockne--All American'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Doors","incorrectAnswers":["Styx","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American rock band released the studio album 'The Soft Parade'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Barbados","incorrectAnswers":["Timor-Leste","Morocco","Oman"],"question":"Bridgetown is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Andrew Johnson","incorrectAnswers":["John Adams","Thomas Jefferson","James Madison"],"question":"Who was the first president to be impeached?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Mikhail Lermontov","incorrectAnswers":["Nikolai Gogol","Mikhail Bulgakov","Alexander Pushkin"],"question":"Which author wrote 'A Hero of Our Time'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Bread","incorrectAnswers":["Cheese","Fruit","Nut"],"question":" What type of food is pitta?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"KFC","incorrectAnswers":["McDonald's","Burger King","Wendy's"],"question":"Which fast food is known for a menu that mainly contains fried chicken?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Octave Mirbeau","incorrectAnswers":["François-René de Chateaubriand","Stendhal","Guy de Maupassant"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Diary of a Chambermaid'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"People's Republic of China","incorrectAnswers":["Tajikistan","Kyrgyzstan","Thailand"],"question":"Which of these countries borders India?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"English","incorrectAnswers":["French","Spanish","Mandarin"],"question":"What is the universally accepted international language of aviation?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Ophthalmology","incorrectAnswers":["Endocrinology","Cardiology","Nephrology"],"question":"What medical field specializes in the eyes?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"That’s my secret, Captain: I’m always angry.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"They call me Mister Tibbs!\"","\"I'm gonna make him an offer he can't refuse.\"","\"I am big! It's the pictures that got small.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Marvel’s The Avengers'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Karl Mordo","incorrectAnswers":["Odin","Tony Stark","Thor"],"question":"Chiwetel Ejiofor plays the role of which character in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tokyo","incorrectAnswers":["Osaka","Kyoto","Sapporo"],"question":"Which Japanese city is served by Narita Airport?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Dravidian","incorrectAnswers":["Turkic","Niger–Congo","Afroasiatic"],"question":"The language 'Telugu' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"James Cameron","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Aliens?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Dachshund","incorrectAnswers":["German Shepherd","Doberman Pinscher","Rottweiler"],"question":"Which German dog breed features short legs and a long body?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Sciatic nerve","incorrectAnswers":["Optic nerve","Lumbar plexus","Ulnar nerve"],"question":"Which is the largest nerve in the Human Body?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Vanuatu","incorrectAnswers":["Barbados","Dominican Republic","Guinea-Bissau"],"question":"Port Vila is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Merlin","incorrectAnswers":["Gandalf","Dumbledore","Gadzook"],"question":"Which magician was an advisor to King Arthur?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"How to Train Your Dragon","incorrectAnswers":["How to Train Your Basilisk","How to Train Your Kraken","How to Train Your Unicorn"],"question":"In which 2010 animated film does Hiccup befriend and then teach an injured mythical creature?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Pierce Brosnan","incorrectAnswers":["Timothy Dalton","Roger Moore","George Lazenby"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in The World is Not Enough?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Nicolaus Copernicus","incorrectAnswers":["Galileo Galilei","Johannes Kepler","Isaac Newton"],"question":"Which Polish astronomer, born in 1473, had his books on heliocentric theory censored by church edict in 1616?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Abu Dhabi","incorrectAnswers":["Rabat","Meccah","Islamabad"],"question":"What is the capital city of United Arab Emirates?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"games and play","incorrectAnswers":["blood serum","the scientific study of baths, bathing and of their application to disease","word origins"],"question":"What is Ludology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"David Bowie","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Madonna","Mika"],"question":"Who released the iconic album 'Ziggy Stardust'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hydrocarbons","incorrectAnswers":["Gases","Petroleum Spirits","Methylated Spirits"],"question":"What are Petrol, Naphta, Kerosine, Diesel and Oil?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kenya","incorrectAnswers":["Ethiopia","Tanzania","Morocco"],"question":"Nairobi is a city in which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Uma Thurman","incorrectAnswers":["Penélope Cruz","Kirsten Dunst","Kristin Scott Thomas"],"question":"Which actress has starred in films including Pulp Fiction and Kill Bill Volume 1?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Roger Moore","incorrectAnswers":["Pierce Brosnan","George Lazenby","Timothy Dalton"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in The Man with the Golden Gun?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Mexico","China","Brazil"],"question":"In what country did the \"Sepoy Mutiny\" occur?\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Andy Warhol","incorrectAnswers":["Salvador Dali","John Lennon","David Bowie"],"question":"Who designed the album sleeve for The Rolling Stones LP \"Sticky Fingers\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Sri Lanka","incorrectAnswers":["Indonesia","Vietnam","Cambodia"],"question":"Colombo is a city in which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"His System Of Wind Force Indicators","incorrectAnswers":["Being the first person to circumnavigate the globe alone","Discovering Hawaii","Surviving adrift at sea for 2 weeks"],"question":"For what is the eighteenth and nineteenth century sailor Sir Francis Beaufort best remembered?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Stephenie Meyer","incorrectAnswers":["Jack Vance","Brandon Sanderson","Robert A. Heinlein"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Eclipse'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["Liechtenstein","United Kingdom","San Marino"],"question":"Which of these countries borders France?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"Who sung the song 'Smooth Criminal'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Chesapeake Bay","incorrectAnswers":["San Francisco Bay","Hudson Bay","Tampa Bay"],"question":"Which bay is marked by Cape Charles and Cape Henry in Virginia, on its northern and southern sides?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Indus","incorrectAnswers":["The Nile","The Ganges","The Euphrates"],"question":"The ancient city of Mohenjo-daro lies along which river in Pakistan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Pol Pot","incorrectAnswers":["Tol Pot","Lol Pot","Bol Pot"],"question":"Who was the leader of the Khmer Rouge?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A man refuses assistance as he ages and begins to his own mind.","incorrectAnswers":["After awakening from a coma, a former assassin wreaks vengeance on those who betrayed her.","In World War II a group of soldiers go behind enemy lines to rescue a paratrooper.","An archaeologist is hired by the government to find the Ark of the Covenant."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie The Father?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Augustus","incorrectAnswers":["Nero","Herod","Pilate"],"question":"Who ruled Rome when Christ was born?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Dwight Eisenhower","incorrectAnswers":["Benjamin Harrison","Abraham Lincoln ","Franklin Pierce"],"question":"Who was the 34th president of the USA, in term during the period 1953–1961?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"An Army Medic refuses to kill and receives the Medal of Honor without firing a shot.","incorrectAnswers":["After his son is captured and taken to Sydney, a clownfish sets out on a journey to bring him home.","A man becomes concerned for his Jewish workforce after witnessing their persecution by the Nazis.","The son of a former boxer is trained by his father for a mixed martial arts tournament."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Hacksaw Ridge?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Melon","incorrectAnswers":["Grape","Apple","Orange"],"question":"What Fruit Is A Cantaloupe?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"It's Raining Men","incorrectAnswers":["Relax","It Takes Two","Hot Child in the City"],"question":"The Weather Girls had a one hit wonder in 1983 with which song?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jamie Foxx","incorrectAnswers":["Hugo Weaving","Warwick Davis","Timothy Spall"],"question":"Which actor has starred in both Django Unchained and Dreamgirls?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The Moon","incorrectAnswers":["The Sun","Halley's Comet","Mars"],"question":"What celestial object was the first for humankind to set foot on?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Rudolph","incorrectAnswers":["Blitzen","Donner","Dancer"],"question":"Which reindeer isn't mentioned in the poem 'The Night Before Christmas''","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Philip K. Dick","incorrectAnswers":["Stanisław Lem","Edgar Rice Burroughs","Stephen King"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep?'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jack Nicholson","incorrectAnswers":["Samuel L. Jackson","Peter O'Toole","Bruce Willis"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Jack Torrance in The Shining?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Poland","incorrectAnswers":["Belgium","Brunei","Japan"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served Bigos?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Austria","incorrectAnswers":["Croatia","Monaco","Liechtenstein"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Italy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Chess","incorrectAnswers":["Scrabble","Life","Monopoly"],"question":"What is the name of the classic board game where players must move pieces around a board in an effort to capture their opponent’s pieces?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Nauru","incorrectAnswers":["Vanuatu","Botswana","Ecuador"],"question":"Yaren District is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Salt","incorrectAnswers":["Sugar","Vinegar","Lemon Juice"],"question":"What is the common name of the chemical compound sodium chloride?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Sherry ","incorrectAnswers":["Ginger","Tomatoes","Bread"],"question":"What would you use the solera process on?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Robert Louis Stevenson","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Agatha Christie","Joseph Conrad"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Treasure Island'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Alien","incorrectAnswers":["Gone with the Wind","A Streetcar Named Desire","Caddyshack"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Ellen Ripley'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Ocean Spray","incorrectAnswers":["Land o' Lakes","Minute Maid","Florida's Natural"],"question":"What is the brand name under which Boston lawyer Marcus Urann marketed cranberry sauce in 1912?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"'Earth Song' was originally released by which musician?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sean Connery","incorrectAnswers":["Timothy Dalton","Daniel Craig","George Lazenby"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in You Only Live Twice?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Golden Hind","incorrectAnswers":["The HMS Victory","The Mary Rose","The Black Pearl"],"question":"With Which Ship Did Francis Drake Circumnavigate The World?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Fleetwood Mac","incorrectAnswers":["Led Zeppelin","Queen","The Who"],"question":"Who Released The 70's Album Entitled \"Tusk\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Suffix","incorrectAnswers":["Prefix","Infix","Interfix"],"question":"What word refers to a set of letters placed after the stem of a word?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Athletics","incorrectAnswers":["Motor racing","Tennis","Figure skating"],"question":"With which sport is Haile Gebreselassie associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rock Around The Clock","incorrectAnswers":["Johnny B Goode","Candy Girl","Old Time Rock and Roll"],"question":"Which Bill Haley song became the U.K.'s first Rock and Roll number one?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The t in 'train'","incorrectAnswers":["The y in 'yellow'","The n in 'no'","The m in 'mother'"],"question":"In phonetics, which of these is an example of a plosive sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Definitely Maybe","incorrectAnswers":["What's the Story (Morning Glory)","Parklife","Greatest Hits"],"question":"What Was The First Number One Album For Oasis?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Protactinium","incorrectAnswers":["Potassium","Lead","Palladium"],"question":"What is the Chemical Element Pa?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Brie Larson","incorrectAnswers":["Cate Blanchett","Jennifer Lawrence","Charlotte Rampling"],"question":"Who won the 2015 Academy Award for Best Leading Actress for playing the role of Ma in Room?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which English rock band released the album 'Magical Mystery Tour'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Roger Moore","incorrectAnswers":["Timothy Dalton","Daniel Craig","George Lazenby"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in Moonraker?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Prague","incorrectAnswers":["Vienna","Oxford","Budapest"],"question":"Which European city is nicknamed the city of a hundred spires?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Camry","incorrectAnswers":["Giulietta","Escalade","Veyron"],"question":"Which of these is a model of car made by Toyota?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Pablo Picasso","incorrectAnswers":["Henri Matisse","Sandro Botticelli","Georges Seurat"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Three Musicians\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Sugar Maple","incorrectAnswers":["American Redbud","Weeping Willow","Elm Tree"],"question":"What is the common name for the tree species Acer saccharum?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1970","incorrectAnswers":["1980","1990","1960"],"question":"In Which Year Was The Boeing 747 Put Into Regular Service?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Silmarillion","incorrectAnswers":["The Decameron","Dead Souls","Welcome to the N.H.K."],"question":"In which book does 'Tuor' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Cabernet Sauvignon","incorrectAnswers":["Pinot Noir","Chardonnay","Merlot"],"question":"What is the most widely planted grape variety in the world?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Haiti","incorrectAnswers":["Vanuatu","Saint Vincent and the Grenadines","Suriname"],"question":"Port-au-Prince is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Robert De Niro","incorrectAnswers":["Peter Lorre","Robert Englund","Joe Pesci"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Travis Bickle in Taxi Driver?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Lord of the Rings","incorrectAnswers":["Harry Potter","Red Rising","The Hunger Games"],"question":"In which book series does 'Frodo Baggins' appear?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A Coven","incorrectAnswers":["A Nest","A Barrow","A Scatter"],"question":"What Is The Name Given To A Group Of Witches?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A kilt","incorrectAnswers":["A kimono","A tuxedo","A dress"],"question":"What item of clothing is traditionally worn with a wide belt as part of Highland dress?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Iraq","incorrectAnswers":["Peru","Austria","Bosnia & Herzegovina"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of The Erbil Citadel?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Depeche Mode","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Dead or Alive","Radiohead"],"question":"Which English band released the song 'Just Can't Get Enough'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Ice Hockey","incorrectAnswers":["Figure skating","Motor racing","Athletics"],"question":"With which sport is Wayne Douglas Gretzky associated?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Banquo","incorrectAnswers":["Lady Macbeth","Macduff","King Duncan"],"question":"Whose ghost appears at the dinner table in \"Macbeth\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Taxi Driver","incorrectAnswers":["The Graduate","Midnight Cowboy","Raging Bull"],"question":"'You talkin to me?' is a line from which 1970's film?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"David Bowie","incorrectAnswers":["The Beatles","William Shatner","Tori Amos"],"question":"The song 'The Man Who Sold the World' had a well-known cover by Nirvana, but who recorded the original?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"René Descartes","incorrectAnswers":["Spinoza","G. W. F. Hegel","Immanuel Kant"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'If you would be a real seeker after truth, it is necessary that at least once in your life you doubt, as far as possible, all things'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Cure","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Snow Patrol"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'Three Imaginary Boys'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"H.G. Wells","incorrectAnswers":["Jules Verne","Aldous Huxley","J.K. Rowling"],"question":"Who wrote \"The Time Machine\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ruby","incorrectAnswers":["Diamond","Sapphire","Emerald"],"question":"In Western cultures, what is the traditional gift for a 40th wedding anniversary?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Don't Stop Me Now\" by Queen","incorrectAnswers":["\"Gimme More\" by Britney Spears","\"Welcome to the Black Parade\" by My Chemical Romance","\"Crazy Train\" by Ozzy Osbourne"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Tonight, I’m gonna have myself a real good time / I feel alive / And the world, I'll turn it inside out, yeah / I'm floating around in ecstasy...\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tokyo","incorrectAnswers":["Kyoto","Osaka","Nagoya"],"question":"In which city is Edo Castle located?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A groundhog","incorrectAnswers":["A prairie dog","A mole","An armadillo"],"question":"Which animal supposedly predicts whether there will be 6 more weeks of winter or an early spring?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Herbivore","incorrectAnswers":["Vegitarian","Vegivore","Omnivore"],"question":"What name is given to animals which only eat plants?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Fudge","incorrectAnswers":["Toffee","Caramel","Marshmallow"],"question":"What is the name of the semisoft sweet good made from sugar, butter & cream?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Canada ","incorrectAnswers":["Russia","China","The USA"],"question":"Which Is The 2nd Largest Country In The World?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Glass","incorrectAnswers":["Cling Film","Diamond","Perspex"],"question":"What see-through substance is made by fusing silica at high temperatures?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Mayflower","incorrectAnswers":["The Mary Rose","The Santa Maria","HMS Victory"],"question":"Of which ship was Miles Standish captain?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Swing Life Away\" by Rise Against","incorrectAnswers":["\"SpongeBob SquarePants Theme\" by Painty the Pirate","\"Old Man\" by Neil Young","\"Chimpan-A to Chimpan-Z\" by Troy McClure"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Am I loud and clear, or am I breaking up? / Am I still your charm, or am I just bad luck? / Are we getting closer, or are we just getting more lost?\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Iraq War","incorrectAnswers":["The Vietnam War","The Ukraine War","Gulf War"],"question":"During which conflict did the Abu Ghraib scandal occur?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Attica! Attica!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Why don't you come up sometime and see me?\"","\"Well, here's another nice mess you've gotten me into!\"","\"Well, I don’t want to survive. I want to live.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Dog Day Afternoon'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"0","incorrectAnswers":["1","2","3"],"question":"How Many Humps Has A Dromedary Camel Got?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Noah","incorrectAnswers":["Isaac","Moses","Adam"],"question":"In the Bible who sent out a dove to find land?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Fresh Prince of Bel-Air","incorrectAnswers":["Family Matters","Full House","Seinfeld"],"question":"Which 1990s sitcom featured a well-to-do California family taking in a streetwise relative from Philadelphia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Gosling","incorrectAnswers":["A Caterpillar","A Joey","A Cub"],"question":"What is the word for a young goose?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Miguel de Cervantes","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Victor Hugo","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Novelas ejemplares ruth nailibeth'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Highbrow","incorrectAnswers":["Bearded","Moûstaché","Quiff"],"question":"Which of these words is used to refer to a very cultured activity?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Tempest","incorrectAnswers":["Othello","A Midsummer Night's Dream","Romeo and Juliet"],"question":"In which of Shakespeare's plays does the character 'Prospero' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Mary Had A Little Lamb","incorrectAnswers":["Twinkle Twinkle Little Star","Humpty Dumpty","Three Blind Mice"],"question":"Which nursery rhyme was the first gramophone recording?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"John Wayne","incorrectAnswers":["Jean-Claude Van Damme","Seth Rogen","John Turturro"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including The Longest Day and The Quiet Man?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Bradley Cooper","incorrectAnswers":["Ryan Reynolds","Jim Carrey","Hugh Jackman"],"question":"Which Hollywood actor has starred in films including Guardians of the Galaxy and American Hustle?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Scooby Doo","incorrectAnswers":["Spongebob Squarepants","Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles","South Park"],"question":"In Which Cartoon Might You Encounter 'The Mystery Machine'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Memphis","incorrectAnswers":["Knoxville","Nashville","Dallas"],"question":"In which US City was Martin Luther King assassinated in 1968?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Drake","incorrectAnswers":["Kanye West","Lil Wayne","Lil Nas X"],"question":"Which hip-hop artist has the most Billboard Music Awards wins?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"You don't understand! I coulda had class. I coulda been a contender. I could've been somebody, instead of a bum, which is what I am.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"You’re going to go through life thinking that girls don’t like you because you’re a nerd. And I want you to know, from the bottom of my heart, that won’t be true. It’ll be because you’re an a**hole.\"","\"I know who I am. I’m the dude playing a dude disguised as another dude!\"","\"Plastics.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'On the Waterfront'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I am a golden god!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"My precious.\"","\"Made it, Ma! Top of the world!\"","\"The stuff that dreams are made of.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Almost Famous'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Dhaka","incorrectAnswers":["Vilnius","Rabat","Lusaka"],"question":"What is the capital city of Bangladesh?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Golden Eagle","incorrectAnswers":["Monarch Butterfly","Jaguar","Chihuahua"],"question":"What animal appears on the flag of Mexico?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Twelfth Night","incorrectAnswers":["Romeo & Juliette","Hamlet","The Taming of the Shrew"],"question":"Which Shakespeare play contains the line 'if music be the food of love play on''?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kathmandu","incorrectAnswers":["Tashkent","Gaborone","Gitega"],"question":"What is the capital city of Nepal?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Ever Fallen In Love","incorrectAnswers":["Smoke on the Water","Wish You Were Here","The Boys Are Back In Town"],"question":"Which Classic 70's Hit Features The Line \"And If I Start A Commotion I Run The Risk Of Losing You And That's Worse\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Soup ","incorrectAnswers":["Stew","Cured Meat","Vegetable"],"question":"Gazpacho is a type of what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","The Who"],"question":"Which British rock band released the song 'Flash', the theme tune to the film 'Flash Gordon'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Thailand","incorrectAnswers":["Vietnam","Laos","Cambodia"],"question":"Which Southeast Asian monarchy was never colonized by Europeans?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1982","incorrectAnswers":["1990","1971","1964"],"question":"In Which Year Did The Falklands Conflict Begin?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Titanic","incorrectAnswers":["The Majestic","The Enormous","The Colossus"],"question":"Which British liner sank on its maiden voyage in 1912?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Michelin Star","incorrectAnswers":["North Star","Flavour Star","Prestige Star"],"question":"What Type Of Star Is Awarded To Restaurants Where The food Is Of Exceptional Quality?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Mike","incorrectAnswers":["Mambo","Mauritius","Mendip"],"question":"What word is used in the NATO Phonetic Alphabet for the letter M?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Dead Sea","incorrectAnswers":["Red Sea","Black Sea","Baltic Sea"],"question":"Which is the only sea below sea level?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Nirvana","incorrectAnswers":["The Rolling Stones","Whitesnake","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which band did Kurt Cobain belong to?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"One","incorrectAnswers":["Blue","Eight","Black"],"question":"What does the word 'um' mean in Portuguese?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Doe","incorrectAnswers":["A Pen","A Mare","A Nanny"],"question":"A female deer is known as what?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Majuro","incorrectAnswers":["Funafuti","Santiago","Nouakchott"],"question":"What is the capital city of Marshall Islands?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The Nose","incorrectAnswers":["The Kidneys","The Skin","The Brain"],"question":"Which Part Of The Body Is Affected By Rhinitis?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Burkina Faso","incorrectAnswers":["Libya","Nigeria","Congo"],"question":"What is the name of the African country that was formerly known as The Republic of Upper Volta?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Amy Adams","incorrectAnswers":["Penélope Cruz","Emma Thompson","Kirsten Dunst"],"question":"Which actress has starred in both Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice and American Hustle?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"With great power comes great responsiblity.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"I love lamp.\"","\"Which would be worse, to live a monster or die as a good man?\"","\"La-dee-da, la-dee-da.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Spider-Man'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"German Bread ","incorrectAnswers":["Belgian Wheat Beer","Dutch Cheese","Danish Butter"],"question":"What is pumpernickel?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"DNA","incorrectAnswers":["The Brain","Dark Matter","Beta Radiation"],"question":"What did Francis Crick and James Watson build a molecular model of in 1953?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Vertigo","incorrectAnswers":["Insomnia","Nausea","Headache"],"question":"Which of these is a movie directed by Alfred Hitchcock?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Franz Kafka","incorrectAnswers":["Émile Zola","Nathaniel Hawthorne","Leo Tolstoy"],"question":"Which author wrote 'In the Penal Colony'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Pacific Ocean","incorrectAnswers":["The Atlantic Ocean","The Indian Ocean","The Caribbean Sea"],"question":"Which surrounding body of water is represented by the blue triangle on the flag of the Solomon Islands?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Igor Stravinsky","incorrectAnswers":["Gustav Holst","Franz Schubert","Joseph Haydn"],"question":"Who Wrote \"The Firebird Suite\" & \"The Ebony Concerto\"? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rihanna","incorrectAnswers":["Drake","Nicki Minaj","Ricky Martin"],"question":"Which singer released the song 'Russian Roulette'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Darwin","incorrectAnswers":["Percy Bysshe Shelley","H. Rider Haggard","Robert Louis Stevenson"],"question":"Which author wrote 'On the Tendency of Species to form Varieties; and on the Perpetuation of Varieties and Species by Natural Means of Selection'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Oedipus","incorrectAnswers":["Jason","Hercules","Perseus"],"question":"In Greek mythology, who solved the riddle of the Sphinx?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Endocrine glands","incorrectAnswers":["Eccrine glands","Salivary glands","Mammary glands"],"question":"In the human body, what is the name given to glands responsible for producing hormones?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Boxing","incorrectAnswers":["Cricket","Rugby Union","Ice Hockey"],"question":"With which sport is Manny Pacquiao associated?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Mauritius","incorrectAnswers":["Afghanistan","Cuba","Greece"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served Dholl Puri?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hydroponics","incorrectAnswers":["Horticulture","Apedology","Anapedics"],"question":"What Is The Method Of Growing Plants Without Soil?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Purple","Yellow","Blue"],"question":"Which colour has highest wavelength in the visible spectrum?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"John Lennon","incorrectAnswers":["Paul McCartney","George Harrison","Ringo Starr"],"question":"Which member of The Beatles famously claimed to be 'More popular than Jesus'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Cars","incorrectAnswers":["Heart And Soul","I Know What Boys Like","Somebody's Watching Me"],"question":"What song did Gary Numan have a hit with in 1980?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Gloria Jones","incorrectAnswers":["The Velvet Underground","Pulp","Johnny Rivers"],"question":"The song 'Tainted Love' had a well-known cover by Soft Cell, but who recorded the original?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"North by Northwest","incorrectAnswers":["Dr. Strangelove or: How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the Bomb","Beauty and the Beast","Three Billboards Outside Ebbing, Missouri"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'An executive goes on the run after being mistaken for a government agent.'","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Heart","incorrectAnswers":["Soul","Blood","Eyes"],"question":"What part of the body does carditis affect?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Rio de Janeiro","incorrectAnswers":["Brasilia","Salvador","Recife"],"question":"What is the name of the second-most populous city in Brazil, following Sao Paulo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Austria and Italy ","incorrectAnswers":["Estonia and Latvia","Iran and Iraq","Morocco and Tunisia"],"question":"What two countries do Tyroleans come from? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Halle Berry","incorrectAnswers":["Frances Fisher","Salma Hayek","Rachel Weisz"],"question":"Which actress played the role of Storm in the X-Men series of films?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Des'ree","incorrectAnswers":["Gary Numan","Edwyn Collins","Brownsville Station"],"question":"'You Gotta Be' was a one hit wonder in 1995 by which artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Bull","incorrectAnswers":["A Dog","A Tiercel","A Hob"],"question":"A male shark is known as what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hg","incorrectAnswers":["KOH","NaCI","CaCO3"],"question":"What is the chemical formula for mercury?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Mexico","incorrectAnswers":["France","Argentina","England"],"question":"Which country hosted the 1986 FIFA World Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Soccer","incorrectAnswers":["Motorsports","Cricket","Rugby"],"question":"Which sport is played at The FA Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Easter Sunday","incorrectAnswers":["Christmas Day","Good Friday","Christmas Eve"],"question":"On which day was the resurrection of Christ?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Maggie Smith","incorrectAnswers":["Kathy Bates","Sandra Bæ Hovedr","Kirsten Dunst"],"question":"Which actress has starred in films including Gosford Park and Downton Abbey?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Dead Man's Chest","incorrectAnswers":["Curse of the Black Pearl","At World's End","On Stranger Tides"],"question":"What was the name of the second 'Pirates of the Caribbean' movie?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Offspring","incorrectAnswers":["Styx","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which punk band from the United States released the studio album 'Smash'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Yellow River","incorrectAnswers":["The Mekong River","The Yangtze River","The Congo River"],"question":"What river is known as China's sorrow because of its flooding?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Beaker","incorrectAnswers":["Ernie","Oscar","Scooter"],"question":"What is the name of the lab assistant who appeared with Dr. Bunsen Honeydew on \"The Muppet Show\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"West Side Story","incorrectAnswers":["The Sound of Music","Oklahoma!","Grease"],"question":"Which famous musical features the song 'I Feel Pretty'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Soil","incorrectAnswers":["Childrens' behaviour and development","Teaching","Flying Reptiles"],"question":"Pedology is the study of ______ ?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Snorri Sturluson","incorrectAnswers":["Sebastian Brant","Agatha Christie","Rainer Maria Rilke"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Heimskringla'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Alcatraz","incorrectAnswers":["Angel Island","The Galapagos Islands","Plymouth Rock"],"question":"Which island, also known as 'The Rock', is a prime stop on a San Francisco tour?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Alice Cooper","incorrectAnswers":["Thin Lizzy","Aerosmith","Fleetwood Mac"],"question":"Who had a hit with School's Out in 1972?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Nine Inch Nails","incorrectAnswers":["Nirvana","The Clash","Blink 182"],"question":"Which band was Trent Reznor the lead vocalist for?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Triangle","incorrectAnswers":["A Square","A Circle","A Rectangle"],"question":"What type of shape might be obtuse or isosceles?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Public Enemy","incorrectAnswers":["Rain Man","The Silence of the Lambs","All About Eve"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Tom Powers'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Absinthe ","incorrectAnswers":["Gin","Port","Whisky"],"question":"Which drink, which has been illegal but is being imported once again, is made from the leaves of the wormwood plant?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Gemini","incorrectAnswers":["Taurus","Leo","Scorpio"],"question":"Which dual-natured astrological sign is associated with Castor & Pollux and means two-faced?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Henry VIII","incorrectAnswers":["Charles I","William the Conqueror","James III"],"question":"Who was the father of Queen Elizabeth I of England?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The llama","incorrectAnswers":["The Panther","The Iguana","The Chimpanzee"],"question":"In Incan mythology, which animal warned about the impending flood?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Rolling Stones","incorrectAnswers":["McFly","Delirious?","Depeche Mode"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Brown Sugar'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"James","incorrectAnswers":["Marshall","Theodore","Thomas"],"question":"What were the first names of US presidents Madison, Monroe, Polk, and Garfield?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"One morning I shot an elephant in my pajamas. How he got in my pajamas, I don't know.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Soylent Green is people!\"","\"I’m going to have to science the s*** out of this.\"","\"Toto, I've a feeling we're not in Kansas anymore.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Animal Crackers'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Asbestos","incorrectAnswers":["Fiberglass","Carbon fiber","Reinforced concrete"],"question":"What is the name of the fibrous mineral formerly used to make fireproof articles?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1983","incorrectAnswers":["1978","1988","1993"],"question":"In which year was Scarface released?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jules Verne","incorrectAnswers":["Victor Hugo","Alphonse Daudet","Edgar Rice Burroughs"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Around the World in Eighty Days'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A woman tries to warn anyone who will listen about the merciless space predators that attacked her.","incorrectAnswers":["24 hours in the lives of three young men the day after a violent riot.","The merciless rivalry between Formula One rivals James Hunt and Niki Lauda.","Explorers travel through a wormhole in space in an attempt to ensure humanity's survival."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Aliens?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"grasshoppers and crickets","incorrectAnswers":["the study and treatment of diseases of the urogenital tract","the biosphere and its relations to the lithosphere and atmosphere","male health and disease"],"question":"What is Orthopterology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"1945","incorrectAnswers":["1935","1955","1965"],"question":"In which year did the Volkswagen Beetle make its first appearance?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Adidas","incorrectAnswers":["Nike","Puma","Reebok"],"question":"Which sports brand is associated with the marketing slogan 'Impossible is Nothing'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Deodoro da Fonseca","incorrectAnswers":["Juscelino Kubitschek","Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva","Fernando Henrique Cardoso"],"question":"Who was the first president of Brazil?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sino-Tibetan","incorrectAnswers":["Austronesian","Uralic","Niger–Congo"],"question":"The language 'Southern Min' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Carnivorous","incorrectAnswers":["Trap","Pitcher","Belljar"],"question":"What is the term for the group of plants that catch and digest insects?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Scorpions","incorrectAnswers":["Rammstein","Sodom","U.D.O."],"question":"Which German rock band released the song 'Rock You Like a Hurricane'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Battlestar Galactica","incorrectAnswers":["Westworld","The Terminator","RoboCop"],"question":"What 2005-2009 TV show featured Cylons and cyborgs?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hobbes","Denis Diderot","Ludwig Wittgenstein"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'We live in the best of all possible worlds'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Sun Also Rises","incorrectAnswers":["Winnie the Pooh","Gone With the Wind","The Horse's Mouth"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Jake Barnes'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1973","incorrectAnswers":["1930","1891","1990"],"question":"In What year did British Honduras become Belize?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Neville Chamberlain","incorrectAnswers":["Winston Churchill","Anthony Eden","Clement Atlee"],"question":"Who was the British Prime Minister at the outbreak of the Second World War?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Madeleine L'Engle","incorrectAnswers":["Nathaniel Hawthorne","Robert E. Howard","Isabel Allende"],"question":"Which author wrote 'A Wrinkle in Time'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Casey Affleck","incorrectAnswers":["Andrew Garfield","Ryan Gosling","Viggo Mortensen"],"question":"Who won the 2016 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Lee Chandler in Manchester by the Sea?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Nigeria","Afghanistan","Australia"],"question":"Which country's flag can be described as 'Three horizontal bands of orange, white, and green, with a blue wheel in the center.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Forbidden fruit","incorrectAnswers":["Bad apple","Posioned chalice","Sour grapes"],"question":"What is the term used to refer to the food that God instructed Adam not to eat in the bible?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Christchurch ","incorrectAnswers":["Wellington","Dunedin","Canterbury"],"question":"Which city in New Zealand is known both as 'The Garden City of the Plains'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1982","incorrectAnswers":["1977","1987","1992"],"question":"Blade Runner was released in which year?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Purple","Yellow","Blue"],"question":"What Colour Are Holly Berries?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The th in 'think'","incorrectAnswers":["The ch in 'cheese'","The j in 'juice'","The t in 'train'"],"question":"In phonetics, which of these is an example of a fricative sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"South America","incorrectAnswers":["Europe","The Middle East","China"],"question":"From which part of the world do sweet potatoes originate?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Wind in the Willows","incorrectAnswers":["Tinker","The Sun Also Rises","The Big Sleep"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Toad'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["The Rolling Stones","The Police","Led Zeppelin"],"question":"Which British rock band released the studio album 'A Night at the Opera'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Clash","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Cheap Trick"],"question":"Which British punk rock band released the song 'London Calling'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Kate Bush","incorrectAnswers":["David Bowie","John Lennon","George Michael"],"question":"Which British recording artist, singer, songwriter, musician and record producer released the studio album 'The Red Shoes'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Orioles","incorrectAnswers":["Ravens","Yankees","Jays"],"question":"Baseball: The Baltimore ________.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Bacardi","incorrectAnswers":["Havana Club","Mount Gay","Captain Morgan's"],"question":"Which brand of rum has a bat on the label?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Agatha Christie","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Louis Stevenson","Charles Dickens","Lewis Carroll"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Murder on the Orient Express'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Don't Stop Believin'\" by Journey","incorrectAnswers":["\"Welcome to the Black Parade\" by My Chemical Romance","\"All Along the Watchtower\" by Bob Dylan","\"All I Want For Christmas Is You\" by Mariah Carey"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Just a small town girl, living in a lonely world.\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tubular pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Soup pasta","Stuffed pasta","Shaped pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is rigatoni?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Led Zeppelin","incorrectAnswers":["Cocteau Twins","Lostprophets","The Kinks"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Good Times Bad Times'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Jeté","incorrectAnswers":["Pirouette","Relevé","Plié"],"question":"What is the term for jumping forward from one foot to the other in ballet?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sunset Boulevard","incorrectAnswers":["Broadcast News","Citizen Kane","Ghost"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Norma Desmond'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Bladder","incorrectAnswers":["Stomach","Kidney","Liver"],"question":"Which organ stores urine?\n","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Alexander the Great","incorrectAnswers":["Napoleon","Julius Caesar","General Custer"],"question":"Who Had a wife named Roxana and a horse named Bacephalus?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Carpenters","incorrectAnswers":["The White Stripes","Sonny & Cher","Salt-N-Pepa"],"question":"Which music had a hit with a song containing the lyrics \"Just like me, they long to be close to you\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"An American Tragedy","incorrectAnswers":["The Tin Drum","Winnie the Pooh","The Remains of the Day"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Clyde Griffiths'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pink Floyd","incorrectAnswers":["Wings","Rudimental","The Alan Parsons Project"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'The Wall'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1971","incorrectAnswers":["1957","1964","1978"],"question":"When was the first email sent?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Audrey Hepburn","incorrectAnswers":["Bette Davis","Catherine Deneuve","Selena Gomez"],"question":"Which actress starred in films including My Fair Lady and Roman Holiday?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Algeria","incorrectAnswers":["China","Mongolia","Bolivia"],"question":"Which of these countries has white on its flag?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"How well, not how much","incorrectAnswers":["Today it's me, tomorrow it will be you","Family over everything","I challenge you"],"question":"What is the meaning of the Latin phrase 'Quam bene non quantum'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Topiary","incorrectAnswers":["Compostation","Drapery","Pottery"],"question":"What is the art of clipping trees and hedges?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Searchers","incorrectAnswers":["Gangs of New York","Scarface","Raiders of the Lost Ark"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Ethan Edwards'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Developed the world's first vaccine (for smallpox).","incorrectAnswers":["Scientist who discovered The Theory of Relativity.","Composer and organist.","Italian explorer who landed in America."],"question":"Which of the following describes Edward Jenner?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Thomas Edison","incorrectAnswers":["Nikola Tesla","Alexander Graham Bell","Albert Einstein"],"question":"Who developed the first practical light bulb?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beach Boys","incorrectAnswers":["The Velvet Underground","The Monkees","Fleetwood Mac"],"question":"Which American rock band released the song 'Wouldn't It Be Nice'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Gazpacho ","incorrectAnswers":["Carpaccio","Alpacho","Fropaccio"],"question":"What is the name of cold Spanish soup made from peppers and tomatoes?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Diseases of the stomach and intestines","incorrectAnswers":["Drug dosage","The origin and spread of diseases","The origin of stars"],"question":"What is Gastroenterology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Smoked Haddock","incorrectAnswers":["Pickled Herring","Spiced Basa","Battered Cod"],"question":"What type of fish is in an omelette Arnold Bennett?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Austroasiatic","incorrectAnswers":["Afroasiatic","Koreanic","Niger–Congo"],"question":"The language 'Khmer' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Buddy Holly, Big Bopper, Richie Valens","incorrectAnswers":["Bill Haley, Johnny Burnette, Chuck Berry ","Fats Domino, Jerry Lee Lewis, Willie Mae Thornton","Elvis Presley, Carl Perkins, Big Joe Turner"],"question":"Which 3 rock stars died in a plane crash on February 3rd 1959?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Low Blood Sugar","incorrectAnswers":["High Cholesterol","High Blood Sugar","Low Cholesterol"],"question":"What Causes Hypoglycemia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["China","Southeast Asia","North America"],"question":"Where in the world are muskmelons originally from?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Skin disease","incorrectAnswers":["Hearing","Fermentation","Games and play"],"question":"What is Dermatopathology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Lungfish","incorrectAnswers":["Shark","Airfish","Bubblefish"],"question":"Which fish is able to breathe air?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Non alcoholic","incorrectAnswers":["With ice","Strong","Served with a straw"],"question":"In cocktails, what does the word 'virgin' mean?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The Amish","incorrectAnswers":["The Shakers","The Hutterites","The Mennonites"],"question":"Which religious sect living primarily in Ohio and southeast Pennsylvania gets its name from a 17th century Swiss Mennonite bishop?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Managua","incorrectAnswers":["Moroni","Lilongwe","Manila"],"question":"What is the capital city of Nicaragua?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Moon landing","incorrectAnswers":["Assassination of JFK","Fall of the Berlin Wall","Invention of the internet"],"question":"What historic event happened on July 20, 1969?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Amelia Earhart ","incorrectAnswers":["Beryl Markham","Mary Johnson","Elise Du Pont"],"question":"Who Was The First Woman To Fly Solo Across The Atlantic Ocean? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Art Nouveau","incorrectAnswers":["Northern Renaissance","Surrealism","High Renaissance"],"question":"The painting \"The Kiss\" by Gustav Klimt is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Algae","incorrectAnswers":["Prawns","Dye","Sunlight"],"question":"Flamingos are not naturally pink. They get their color from ________.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Vienna","incorrectAnswers":["Baku","Ashgabat","Prague"],"question":"What is the capital city of Austria?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Edmonton","incorrectAnswers":["Calgary","Toronto","Vancouver"],"question":"Which Canadian city is nicknamed 'Oil City'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Virginia Woolf","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","George Orwell","Joseph Conrad"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Mrs Dalloway'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Russia ","incorrectAnswers":["Poland","India","Canada"],"question":"Lake Ladoga Is The Largest Lake In Which Country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Pygmies","incorrectAnswers":["Mayans","Inuits","Bantus"],"question":"Which ethnic group of people living in Congo's Ituri Forest are the shortest in the world, with an average height of about 4'8''?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Morocco","incorrectAnswers":["Martinique","Mali","Moldova"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.ma' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Isaac Asimov","incorrectAnswers":["Ursula K. Le Guin","Philip K. Dick","Stephen King"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Lucky Starr series'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1992","incorrectAnswers":["1987","1997","2002"],"question":"When was the first SMS message sent?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tubular pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Ribbon pasta","Shaped pasta","Strand pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is macaroni?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Potassium hydrogen tartrate","incorrectAnswers":["Sodium hydroxide","Trichloromethane","Methane"],"question":"What chemical compound makes cream of tartar?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Horse's Mouth","incorrectAnswers":["The Member of the Wedding","Breakfast at Tiffany's","On the Road"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Gulley Jimson'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Eurythmics","incorrectAnswers":["U2","Blondie","Evanescence"],"question":"Which band did Annie Lennox belong to?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Ewe","incorrectAnswers":["A Bitch","A Soar","A Cow"],"question":"What is a female sheep known as?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"Which American singer, songwriter and dancer released the song 'Love Never Felt So Good'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Gin ","incorrectAnswers":["Rum","Vodka","Whiskey"],"question":"Which alcoholic drink would you need to make the cocktail Tom Collins?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A watch","incorrectAnswers":["A charm","A rag","An exaltation"],"question":"What is the word for a group of nightingales?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Third Reich","incorrectAnswers":["New Holland","Marburg Republic","Holy Roman Empire"],"question":"What term refers to Germany between 1933 and 1945?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Hazel","incorrectAnswers":["Willow","Birch","Oak"],"question":"Which Wood Are Divining Rods Usually Made From?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Elton John","incorrectAnswers":["Mika","Madonna","Eric Clapton"],"question":"Which musician released 'Your Song'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"MC Hammer","incorrectAnswers":["Vanilla Ice","Snoop Dogg","Sir Mix-a-Lot"],"question":"Stanley Burrell Is The Real Name Of Which Popular 90's Musician?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1985","incorrectAnswers":["1979","1965","1950"],"question":"In What Year Did Mikhail Gorbachev Become Leader Of The Soviet Union?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Chess","incorrectAnswers":["Checkers","Backgammon","Go"],"question":"In 1988, Bobby Fischer invented a new type of clock that has since become widely used in which board game?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Liverpool","incorrectAnswers":["Manchester","Newcastle","Leeds"],"question":"Which Northern UK English city Did The Beatles Come From?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Cuba","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","Ivory Coast","Russia"],"question":"Ropa Vieja is a dish that is most associated with which part of the world?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Dean Martin","incorrectAnswers":["Steve Martin","Tim Allen","James Wood"],"question":"Famed as a member of the Rat Pack, who died on Christmas day 1995?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ramadan","incorrectAnswers":["Passover","Yom Kippur","Lent"],"question":"What is the name for the Islamic fasting period?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Spain","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","France","Chile"],"question":"In which country do they eat 12 grapes as the clock strikes midnight (one each time the clock chimes) on New Year's Eve?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1911","incorrectAnswers":["1945","1820","1515"],"question":"In What Year Was The Chinese Republic Established?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The Dial Telephone","incorrectAnswers":["The Hearing Aid","The Telegram","The Microphone"],"question":"What Communication Aid Was Invented In 1905 By American Undertaker Almon Strowger","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Uriah Heep"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Please Please Me'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Coldplay","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British band released the song 'Clocks'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Reykjavik","incorrectAnswers":["Madrid","Dublin","Lisbon"],"question":"What Is The Most Westerly European Capital City?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Islamabad","incorrectAnswers":["Zagreb","Tallinn","Tehran"],"question":"What is the capital city of Pakistan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Netherlands","incorrectAnswers":["Saint Lucia","Malaysia","Benin"],"question":"Amsterdam is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Birdman or (The Unexpected Virtue of Ignorance)","incorrectAnswers":["American Sniper","Boyhood","The Grand Budapest Hotel"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2014?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Geneva","incorrectAnswers":["Budapest","Valencia","Prague"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Switzerland?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Ha*Ash","incorrectAnswers":["The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American Latin pop duo released the album 'En vivo'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Spain ","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","England","France"],"question":"Which Country's Royalty Paid For Christopher Columbus 's First Voyage Across The Atlantic?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Rum","incorrectAnswers":["Brandy","Whiskey","Tequila"],"question":"What liquor made from molasses has caramel added to make the darker varieties?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Cria","incorrectAnswers":["A Duckling","A Fry","A Chick"],"question":"What is a baby alpaca known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Collector","incorrectAnswers":["Alexander Pierce","Howard Stark","Groot"],"question":"In the Marvel Cinematic Universe, which character is played by Benicio Del Toro?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ecuador ","incorrectAnswers":["Latvia","Liberia","Indonesia"],"question":"Which country has taken its name from a line of latitude?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1066","incorrectAnswers":["1000","1120","1257"],"question":"William the Conqueror was crowned on Christmas day, but in what year?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"FC Dallas","incorrectAnswers":["Dallas Bills","Dallas United","Real Dallas"],"question":"Which of these is a soccer team based in Dallas?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Brazil","incorrectAnswers":["Costa Rica","France","Italy"],"question":"In which country is cachaca a popular drink?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Diapers","incorrectAnswers":["Formula Milk","Medicine","Food"],"question":"What type of baby product is Huggies?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Jenny","incorrectAnswers":["Brenda","Lisa","Julie"],"question":"Who Is Tommy Tutone Trying To Call When He Dials \"867 5309\"","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ten","incorrectAnswers":["Green","Three","White"],"question":"What does the word 'zehn' mean in German?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Brakes","incorrectAnswers":["Steering Wheel","Engine","Exhaust Pipe"],"question":"In a car, what might be disc or drum?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Syracuse ","incorrectAnswers":["Albany","Uticer","Ithaca"],"question":"Which port of Sicily shares its name with a city in New York State?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Napoleon","incorrectAnswers":["Charlemagne","De Gaulle","Joan of Arc"],"question":"Which French Ruler Was Finally Defeated In 1815?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Germany","Austria-Hungary","Bulgaria"],"question":"Which of the following was NOT one of the Ottoman Empire's major allies during World War I?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Cure","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Snow Patrol"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'Disintegration'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Enid Blyton","incorrectAnswers":["J. R. R. Tolkien","Lewis Carroll","Oscar Wilde"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Famous Five'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The Best a Man Can Get","incorrectAnswers":["Quality never goes out of style","Easy, breezy, beautiful….","Maybe she's born with it"],"question":"Which marketing slogan would you associate with Gillette?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"A Hogshead","incorrectAnswers":["An Alekeg","A Bogteen","A Grond"],"question":"Which archaic imperial unit of measure is equivalent to 54 gallons?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Agatha Christie","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Louis Stevenson","Charles Dickens","Lewis Carroll"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Partners in Crime'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Niger","incorrectAnswers":["Congo","Zaïre","Benue"],"question":"Name the longest river in Nigeria.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sigourney Weaver","incorrectAnswers":["Anne Bancroft","Angela Lansbury","Katharine Hepburn"],"question":"Which actress played the role of Ellen Ripley in Alien?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Afroasiatic","incorrectAnswers":["Turkic","Austroasiatic","Japonic"],"question":"The language 'North Levantine Arabic' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tehran","incorrectAnswers":["Isfahan","Shiraz","Tabriz"],"question":"What is the capital of Iran?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Holy Roman Empire","incorrectAnswers":["The Roman Empire","Napoleon's French Empire","The German Empire"],"question":"What did Nazi Germany refer to as The First Reich?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"San Jose","incorrectAnswers":["Andorra la Vella","Port of Spain","Majuro"],"question":"What is the capital city of Costa Rica?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Ugly American","incorrectAnswers":["The Quiet American","The Americanization of Emily","An American in Vietnam"],"question":"Which 1963 drama features Marlon Brando as the U.S. Ambassador to an Asian country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"affricative","incorrectAnswers":["nasal","plosive","approximant"],"question":"In phonetics, the j in 'juice' is an example of what kind of sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Belize","incorrectAnswers":["El Salvador","Honduras","Nicaragua"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Mexico?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Schnapps","incorrectAnswers":["Rakia","Tequila","Mama Juana"],"question":"Which of these is a popular drink in Austria?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Breathless","incorrectAnswers":["The 400 Blows","Jules and Jim","Contempt"],"question":"Which 1959 French New Wave film, with a story provided by Truffaut, features Belmondo as a hoodlum who kills a cop?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tomato juice","incorrectAnswers":["Lemonade","Iced tea","Milk"],"question":"What is the state beverage of Ohio?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Apparent Magnitude","incorrectAnswers":["Apparent Luminosity","Apparent Intensity","Apparent Radiance"],"question":"In astronomy, what is the term for the measurement of the brightness of stars?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ares","incorrectAnswers":["Athena","Hephaestus","Zeus"],"question":"Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman god Mars?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Aves","incorrectAnswers":["Birdilia","Flowana","Aerilys"],"question":"In the animal kingdom, if reptiles are in class reptilia, then birds are in class ____?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The Netherlands","incorrectAnswers":["France","Poland","Turkey"],"question":"From what country does Advocaat originate?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"James and the Giant Peach","incorrectAnswers":["John and the Giant Apple","Jack and the Giant Pear","Jonah and the Giant Pineapple"],"question":"In which book did Roald Dahl tell the story of a boy's adventure in a giant piece of fruit?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Turkey","incorrectAnswers":["Ghana","Bhutan","Central America"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served Döner Kebab?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mogadishu","incorrectAnswers":["Tashkent","Dushanbe","Majuro"],"question":"What is the capital city of Somalia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Texas","incorrectAnswers":["Florida","Michigan","California"],"question":"In which US state is the Houston Space Centre?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"San Francisco 49ers","incorrectAnswers":["San Francisco Jaguars","San Francisco Pistons","San Francisco Predators"],"question":"Which of these is an American Football team based in San Francisco?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"New York Knicks","incorrectAnswers":["New York 76ers","New York Penguins","New York Eagles"],"question":"Which of these is a basketball team based in New York?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The flamingo","incorrectAnswers":["The pelican","The stork","The heron"],"question":"What is the name of the bird whose scientific name is Phoenicopterus ruber roseus?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bamako","incorrectAnswers":["Lomé","Managua","Zagreb"],"question":"What is the capital city of Mali?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"2009","incorrectAnswers":["2007","2011","2013"],"question":"In which year was Up first released in the cinema?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Greece","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","Spain","Egypt"],"question":"Which country was served by Olympic Airlines?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Paris","incorrectAnswers":["Stockholm","Berlin","Leipzig"],"question":"Which of these cities is in France?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Two ","incorrectAnswers":["Five","Four","Three"],"question":"How many standard bottles of champagne are in a magnum?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jack Nicholson","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Shaw","James Stewart","Harrison Ford"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Randle Patrick McMurphy in One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Bob Cratchit","incorrectAnswers":["Billy Catchit","Norman Patchit","Gregory Snatchit"],"question":"What is the name of Tiny Tim's father in the story, 'A Christmas Carol'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Wind","incorrectAnswers":["Percussion","String","Keyboard"],"question":"What type of instrument is a harmonica?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Switzerland","incorrectAnswers":["Poland","Albania","Kazakhstan"],"question":"Bern is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Marlon Brando","incorrectAnswers":["Anthony Perkins","Bruce Willis","Humphrey Bogart"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Terry Malloy in On the Waterfront?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Hi-hat","incorrectAnswers":["Snare","Ride cymbals","Tom-tom"],"question":"What is the name of the pair of cymbals on a drum kit controlled by a foot pedal?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Terminator","incorrectAnswers":["RoboCop","Aliens","Predator"],"question":"Which movie from 1984 features the line 'It doesn't feel pity, or remorse, or fear. And it absolutely will not stop... ever, until you are dead!'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I’m already pregnant. So, what other shenanigans could I get myself into?\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"This is Sparta!\"","\"Sawyer, you're going out a youngster, but you've t to come back a star!\"","\"You shall not pass!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Juno'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"94","incorrectAnswers":["97","89","91"],"question":"What is the result of the mathematical operation obtained by subtracting the number of Snow White's dwarfs from the original title number of 'Disney Dalmatians'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Milwaukee Bucks","incorrectAnswers":["Milwaukee Heat","Milwaukee Reds","Milwaukee Pirates"],"question":"Which of these is a basketball team based in Milwaukee?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Larva","incorrectAnswers":["Bulba","Curla","Meta"],"question":"The four stages in the lifecycle of an insect are: egg, adult, pupa, and ________.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Annex","incorrectAnswers":["Appendix","Addendum","Supplement"],"question":"What is the word for an auxiliary building near the main one?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Aphrodite","incorrectAnswers":["Athena","Hera","Minerva"],"question":"Who is the Greek equivalent of the roman god Venus?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Becherovka","incorrectAnswers":["Sangria","Seco Herrerano","Koskenkorva Viina"],"question":"Which of these drinks would you associate with The Czech Republic?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Boar","incorrectAnswers":["A Drone","A Macho","A Tom"],"question":"What is a male panda known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"European Robin","incorrectAnswers":["African Hawk","Albatross ","Grey Pigeon "],"question":"Which garden bird is famous for their red breast and beady eyes?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Laura Dern","incorrectAnswers":["Kathy Bates","Scarlett Johansson","Florence Pugh"],"question":"Who won the 2019 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress for playing the role of Nora Fanshaw in Marriage Story?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"17th century","incorrectAnswers":["18th century","19th century","20th century"],"question":"In which century did the Thirty Years' War take place?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Nile","incorrectAnswers":["The Yangtze","The Ganges","The Mississippi"],"question":"What river is the Temple of Karnak near?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1985","incorrectAnswers":["1970","1975","1980"],"question":"In which year was Back to the Future first released in the cinema?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Japan","incorrectAnswers":["China","Vietnam","India"],"question":"Which country uses the 'yen' for currency?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Copper and Zinc","incorrectAnswers":["Iron and Bronze","Silver and Steel","Tin and Gold"],"question":"Which two metals make up brass?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Whale","incorrectAnswers":["Echnaton","Yeti","Aliens"],"question":"In the novel Moby Dick, what do Ahab and Ishmael encounter?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Carbon","incorrectAnswers":["Oxygen","Hydrogen","Gold"],"question":"Coal is composed of which element?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"drug dosage","incorrectAnswers":["origin of life","diseases of stomach and intestines","poisons"],"question":"What is Posology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Ursula K. Le Guin","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Jack Vance","George R. R. Martin"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Word for World Is Forest'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Morocco","incorrectAnswers":["Romania","Zambia","Iraq"],"question":"Rabat is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Brutus","incorrectAnswers":["Puck","Hermia","Oberon"],"question":"Which of the following characters does not appear in Shakespeare's 'A Midsummer Night's Dream'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Soccer","Badminton","Volleyball"],"question":"Within Which Sport Might You Encounter The Cyclops System?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Jill","incorrectAnswers":["A Jenny","A Cow","A Soar"],"question":"A female ferret is known as what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"1984","incorrectAnswers":["1986","1988","1990"],"question":"In what year was Band-Aid's Do They Know It's Christmas the UK Christmas chart-topping record?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Sri Lanka","incorrectAnswers":["India","Nepal","Pakistan"],"question":"Ceylon officially became which country on May 22, 1972?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jacques-Louis David","incorrectAnswers":["Vincent van Gogh","Édouard Manet","Pierre-Auguste Renoir"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Portrait of Madame Recamier\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Are you not entertained?\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Nobody puts Baby in a corner.\"","\"La-dee-da, la-dee-da.\"","\"I'll have what she's having.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Gladiator'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Bull","incorrectAnswers":["A Hob","A Cob","A Billy"],"question":"What would you call a male manatee?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Buck","incorrectAnswers":["A Stallion","A Dog","A Boar"],"question":"A male rabbit is known as what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Antarctica","incorrectAnswers":["Europe","Asia","South America"],"question":"What continent is the Bellingshausen Sea next to? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"One","incorrectAnswers":["Yellow","Eight","Ten"],"question":"In Spanish, what is the meaning of the word 'uno'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Kra–Dai","Sino-Tibetan","Austroasiatic"],"question":"The language 'Northern Pashto' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Moschino","incorrectAnswers":["Valentino","Givenchy","Prada"],"question":"Which of the following fashion houses is famous for its colorful, eccentric designs, often made with unusual materials?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"society","incorrectAnswers":["bones","the preparation of books and manuscripts","nematodes"],"question":"What is Sociology the study of?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"carbon copy","incorrectAnswers":["clear cut","courtesy confirmation","cordially confirm"],"question":"What does the abbreviation cc: near the bottom of a letter mean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Afghanistan","incorrectAnswers":["Kyrgyzstan","Bosnia and Herzegovina","Australia"],"question":"Which of these countries has black on its flag?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ford","incorrectAnswers":["Volkswagen","BMW","Porsche"],"question":"Which motoring brand is associated with the marketing slogan 'Go Further'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Four","incorrectAnswers":["Five","Six","Two"],"question":"What does the word 'vier' mean in Dutch?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Chile","incorrectAnswers":["Argentina","Mexico","Brazil"],"question":"Which of these countries is between Bolivia and the Pacific Ocean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Russia","incorrectAnswers":["Japan","France","Canada"],"question":"Which country was suspended from the G8 in 2014?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Bengali","incorrectAnswers":["Quechua","Portuguese","Swahili"],"question":"Which of these languages would you find spoken in India?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Vladimir Nabokov","incorrectAnswers":["Ayn Rand","Kurt Vonnegut","Mikhail Bulgakov"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Annotated Lolita (1991 Vintage Books ed.)'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"War of the Worlds","incorrectAnswers":["The Time Machine","1984","The Invisible Man"],"question":"What was the title of the most famous broadcast of \"The Mercury Theater on the Air,\" which aired on October 30, 1938 and caused panic across the United States?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"New Radicals","incorrectAnswers":["The Proclaimers","Vicki Lawrence","Brownsville Station"],"question":"'You Get What You Give' was a one hit wonder in 1999 by which artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Ursula K. Le Guin","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Jack Vance","George R. R. Martin"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Hainish Cycle'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Japan","incorrectAnswers":["Mongolia","Nigeria","Angola"],"question":"In what country do people speak the Language they call Nihongo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Schindler's List","incorrectAnswers":["The Fugitive","In the Name of the Father","The Piano"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1993?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jared Leto","incorrectAnswers":["Peter Cushing","Kenneth Branagh","Luke Evans"],"question":"Which actor has played roles in films including Suicide Squad and Requiem for a Dream?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Hudson Bay","incorrectAnswers":["Erie Bay","Superior Bay","Georgian Bay"],"question":"James Bay, located in Ontario and Quebec, is the southern arm of which larger bay?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Michael Crichton","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Stephen Chbosky","David Lynch"],"question":"Which best selling American writer wrote and directed the sci-fi film Westworld?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Matthew McConaughey","incorrectAnswers":["Christian Bale","Bruce Dern","Leonardo DiCaprio"],"question":"Who won the 2013 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Ron Woodroof in Dallas Buyers Club?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Macrosmatic","incorrectAnswers":["Nudiustertian","Conjubilant","Gubbins"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'having a good sense of smell'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Buffalo Sabres","incorrectAnswers":["Buffalo Colts","Buffalo Dynamo","Buffalo Packers"],"question":"Which of these is a hockey team based in Buffalo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Rolling Stones","incorrectAnswers":["McFly","Delirious?","Depeche Mode"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'Aftermath'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The nature of knowledge","incorrectAnswers":["Mind-altering drugs","Characterizing criminals","The climate"],"question":"What is Epistemology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Firman","incorrectAnswers":["Yarborough","Tittynope","Funambulist"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'in Turkey and some other Oriental countries, a decree or mandate issued by the sovereign'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"San Diego","incorrectAnswers":["San Francisco","Los Angeles","Sacramento"],"question":"Which California city was a whaling port in the mid-1800s and is located 12 miles north of Mexico?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Dry Ice","incorrectAnswers":["Chloroform","Baking Soda","Epsom salt"],"question":"What is solid carbon dioxide commonly known as?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Kites","incorrectAnswers":["Hot Air Balloons","Starlings","Fireworks"],"question":"What would you expect to see in the skies above the Punjab during the Basant festival, marking the start of spring?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ulaanbaatar","incorrectAnswers":["Skopje","Gitega","Niamey"],"question":"What is the capital city of Mongolia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"My Life As a Man","incorrectAnswers":["The Tin Drum","Breakfast at Tiffany's","The Sound and the Fury"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Nathan Zuckerman'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Brittany","incorrectAnswers":["Provence","Normandy","Corsica"],"question":"What coastal region of France has over 200,000 speakers of a Celtic language?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"gelt","incorrectAnswers":["schmuck","kvetch","mensch"],"question":"What is the Yiddish word for money?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"54","incorrectAnswers":["64","9","16"],"question":"How many colored squares does a Rubiks Cube have?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Pride and Prejudice","incorrectAnswers":["The Fault in Our Stars","Ship of Fools","War and Peace"],"question":"In which book does 'Charles Bingley' appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The FIFA World Cup","incorrectAnswers":["The Grand National","The Davis Cup","The Americas Cup"],"question":"Which of these is a Soccer competition?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Cubism","incorrectAnswers":["Baroque","Post Impressionism","Renaissance"],"question":"The painting \"The Bathers\" by Paul Cézanne is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Loggia","incorrectAnswers":["Terrace","Gazebo","Patio"],"question":"Which of these architectural features is an outdoor corridor or gallery with a fully covered roof  and an outer wall that is open to the elements?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"When two girls move to the country, they have adventures with the forest spirits who live nearby.","incorrectAnswers":["When a girl is possessed, her mother seeks the help of two priests to save her.","A chaotic clown causes a masked vigilante one of his greatest tests.","A man sees the spotlight turned on him following his wife's disappearance."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie My Neighbour Totoro?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Poland","incorrectAnswers":["Iceland","Macedonia","Slovenia"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Kraków?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Mississippi","incorrectAnswers":["Hudson","Ohio","Rio Grande"],"question":"Along which river do the adventures of Tom Sawyer take place?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Iron","Illness","Idle"],"question":"What word is used in the NATO Phonetic Alphabet for the letter I?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Harp","incorrectAnswers":["Bagpipe","Cowbell","Cornett"],"question":"Which of these is a stringed instrument?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1977","incorrectAnswers":["1972","1982","1987"],"question":"In which year was Star Wars released?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Amman","incorrectAnswers":["Kuwait City","Antalya","Cairo"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Jordan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Penguin","incorrectAnswers":["Stork","Eagle","Swan"],"question":"Which of these birds can swim but not fly?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Paris","incorrectAnswers":["New York","London","Sydney"],"question":"Macaulay Caulkin's folks left him \"Home Alone\" in the original 1990 movie. Where did they go?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1994","incorrectAnswers":["1986","1990","1998"],"question":"Forrest Gump was released in which year?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Europe","incorrectAnswers":["Central America","China","Central Asia"],"question":"Where in the world are parsnips originally from?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Super Mario Bros.","incorrectAnswers":["Zelda","Call of Duty","Halo"],"question":"If you're killing a goomba, what game are you playing?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Thailand","incorrectAnswers":["Senegal","Mali","Chad"],"question":"Which of these countries has white on its flag?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Canelazo","incorrectAnswers":["Kumis","Rakı","Tuba"],"question":"Which of these drinks would you associate with Equador?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Normandy","incorrectAnswers":["Brittany","Alsace","Burgundy"],"question":"Which French region is named after invading Vikings of the mid-9th century?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Parade's End","incorrectAnswers":["Lolita","The English Patient","My Life As a Man"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Christopher Tietjens'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Billy","incorrectAnswers":["A Macho","A Drone","A Ram"],"question":"A male goat is known as what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Holocaust","incorrectAnswers":["Auchterarder","Blitzkrieg","Luftwaffe"],"question":"Which word describes the Nazi genocide of Jews?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"War and Peace","incorrectAnswers":["Doctor Zhivago","Crime and Punishment","The Gambler"],"question":"Which of these famous Russian novels was written by Leo Tolstoy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Moo Shoo","incorrectAnswers":["Kung Pao","General Tso's Chicken","Lo Mein"],"question":"What Chinese dish is traditionally made of shredded pork stir-fried with eggs, bamboo shoots, other vegetables, and served in thin pancakes?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Taichung","incorrectAnswers":["Wellington","Busan","Kuala Lumpur"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Taiwan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Marcel Marceau","incorrectAnswers":["Jacques Tati","Charlie Chaplin","Buster Keaton"],"question":"Which legendary mime picked up a 1955 Emmy for Best Specialty Act?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"a more inclusive term for theology","incorrectAnswers":["the history, languages, and cultures of the Indian subcontinent","the Sumerians","crayfish"],"question":"What is Hierology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Judi Dench","incorrectAnswers":["Kathy Bates","Brenda Blethyn","Rachel Griffiths"],"question":"Who won the 1998 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress for playing the role of Queen Elizabeth I in Shakespeare in Love?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Well, here's another nice mess you've gotten me into!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"My precious.\"","\"After all, tomorrow is another day!\"","\"Gentlemen, you can't fight in here! This is the War Room!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Sons of the Desert'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I have had it with these mother—— snakes on this mother—— plane!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Not my tempo.\"","\"Oh, Jerry, don't let's ask for the moon. We have the stars.\"","\"Tell 'em to go out there with all they got and win just one for the Gipper.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Snakes on a Plane'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sino-Tibetan","incorrectAnswers":["Turkic","Niger–Congo","Uralic"],"question":"The language 'Wu Chinese' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Charreada","incorrectAnswers":["Bandy","Korfball","Futsal"],"question":"Which of these is a traditional Mexican sport?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Athletics","incorrectAnswers":["Hockey","Table tennis","Gymnastics"],"question":"With which sport is Michael Johnson associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Blur","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Our Lady Peace","Feeder"],"question":"Which English alternative rock band released the studio album 'Think Tank'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Afroasiatic","incorrectAnswers":["Indo-European","Turkic","Dravidian"],"question":"The language 'Sanaani Spoken Arabic' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Kobe","incorrectAnswers":["Sapporo","Kyoto","Osaka"],"question":"Which Japanese city is famous for the beef it produces?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The 1990s","incorrectAnswers":["The 1980s","The 2000s","The 1970s"],"question":"In which decade was Hong Kong returned to China?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Swimmer","incorrectAnswers":["The English Patient","Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man","Nine Stories"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Neddy Merrill'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Nero","incorrectAnswers":["Claudius","Augustine","Caligula"],"question":"Which Roman Emperor is said to have fiddled while Rome burned?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The f in 'fish'","incorrectAnswers":["The d in 'door'","The n in 'no'","The y in 'yellow'"],"question":"In phonetics, which of these is an example of a fricative sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Elijah Wood","incorrectAnswers":["Tim Roth","Timothy Spall","Hugo Weaving"],"question":"Which actor has appeared in films including Wilfred and Sin City?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"To Kill A Mockingbird","incorrectAnswers":["The Wind in the Willows","The Age of Innocence","Winnie the Pooh"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Atticus Finch'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Nobody makes me bleed my own blood. Nobody!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Are you not entertained?\"","\"I have had it with these mother—— snakes on this mother—— plane!\"","\"What is this? A center for ants? How can we be expected to teach children to learn how to read…if they can’t even fit inside the building?\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Dodgeball: A True Underdog Story'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"King Crimson","incorrectAnswers":["Mogwai","Deep Purple","Sade"],"question":"Which British progressive rock band released the album 'In the Court of the Crimson King'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Borneo & Sumatra","incorrectAnswers":["Bali & Lombok","Sulawesi & Java","New Guinea & Komodo"],"question":"Which 2 Islands Are The Natural Habitat Of The Orang-Utan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Austria","incorrectAnswers":["Uzbekistan","Estonia","France"],"question":"In which country would you find the City of Salzburg?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Echo","incorrectAnswers":["Aphrodite","Nemesis","Leto"],"question":"Who according to mythology was a nymph who pined away over Narcissus until only her voice was left?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Kurt Vonnegut","incorrectAnswers":["Vladimir Nabokov","Edgar Allan Poe","Stanisław Lem"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Cat's Cradle'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["China","Southeast Asia","South America"],"question":"From which part of the world does okra originate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Brazil","incorrectAnswers":["Germany","Italy","Argentina"],"question":"Which country has won the most FIFA World Cups?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Police","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Wings","Ultravox"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Every Breath You Take'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Lewis Carroll","incorrectAnswers":["Enid Blyton","George Orwell","Charles Dickens"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Hunting of the Snark'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Somalia","incorrectAnswers":["United States of America","Guyana","Mauritius"],"question":"Mogadishu is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Woodwind","incorrectAnswers":["Percussion","Stringed","Brass"],"question":"What type of instrument is a piccolo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Police","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Wings","Ultravox"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'So Lonely'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"‎‎Edvard Munch","incorrectAnswers":["James Abbott McNeill Whistler","Henri Matisse","Jean-François Millet"],"question":"Which artist painted \"The Scream\"","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Brandenburg ","incorrectAnswers":["Bavaria","Saxony","Bremen"],"question":"Which German federal state surrounds the city of Berlin?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Spiders","incorrectAnswers":["Bones","Rheumatic diseases","Buddha"],"question":"What is Arachnology the study of?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Clash","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Cheap Trick"],"question":"Which British punk rock band released the album 'London Calling'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Heimdall","incorrectAnswers":["Thor","Ysdragil","Baldur"],"question":"Who is the Norse Watchman of the Gods ?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Waitresses","incorrectAnswers":["Haddaway","Spandau Ballet","Right Said Fred"],"question":"Who had a hit in 1982 with I Know What Boys Like?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Sawyer, you're going out a youngster, but you've t to come back a star!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Hello, gorgeous.\"","\"You don't understand! I coulda had class. I coulda been a contender. I could've been somebody, instead of a bum, which is what I am.\"","\"I'll get you, my pretty, and your little dog, too!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film '42nd Street'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Kangaroo","incorrectAnswers":["Panda","Eagle","Moose"],"question":"Which animal would you associate with the Qantas logo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Sherlock Holmes","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Langdon series","Voyages Extraordinaires","Harry Potter"],"question":"In which book series does 'Dr. John Watson' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Omnipotence","incorrectAnswers":["Omniscience","Omnipresence","Omnivore"],"question":"What is the state or quality of being all-powerful?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Colin Firth","incorrectAnswers":["Javier Bardem","Jeff Bridges","Jesse Eisenberg"],"question":"Who won the 2010 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of King George VI in The King's Speech?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Basoon","incorrectAnswers":["Flute","Clarinet","Piccolo"],"question":"What is the name of the lowest pitched woodwind instrument?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Big Kahuna burger ","incorrectAnswers":["Royale With Cheese ","Dunkin' Donuts","KFC Family Bucket"],"question":"What was Brett's last supper in the film Pulp Fiction?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Christopher Tolkien","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Gaiman","J. R. R. Tolkien","J. K. Rowling"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Unfinished Tales'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The Scoville scale","incorrectAnswers":["The Heat index","The Shearer Factor","The Spiciness Gauge"],"question":"What is the name of the scale used to measure the heat level of chili peppers?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Claude Monet","incorrectAnswers":["Leonardo da Vinci","Hokusai","Pieter Bruegel the Elder"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Impression, Sunrise\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ben Kingsley","incorrectAnswers":["Dustin Hoffman","Jack Lemmon","Paul Newman"],"question":"Who won the 1982 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Mahatma Gandhi in Gandhi?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Cubism","incorrectAnswers":["post-impressionism","Northern Renaissance","Ukiyo-e"],"question":"The painting \"Guernica\" by ‎Pablo Picasso is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Kangaroo","incorrectAnswers":["Squirrel","Crocodile","Cow"],"question":"A 'Boomer\" Is The Male Of Which Animal?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Underground","incorrectAnswers":["In a tree","Underwater","In a damn"],"question":"Where Does A Gopher Make Its Home?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Oh, Jerry, don't let's ask for the moon. We have the stars.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Stella! Hey, Stella!\"","\"If you build it, he will come.\"","\"You motorboatin’ son of a b****!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Now, Voyager'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Atlanta Hawks","incorrectAnswers":["Atlanta Suns","Atlanta Nationals","Atlanta Rockets"],"question":"Which of these is a basketball team based in Atlanta?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"pollen","incorrectAnswers":["musical instruments","drugs","study of refuse and trash"],"question":"What is Palynology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Forseti","incorrectAnswers":["Baldur","Thor","Odin"],"question":"Who is the Norse god of justice?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Guns N' Roses","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American hard rock band released the song 'Welcome to the Jungle'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Thailand","incorrectAnswers":["Uzbekistan","Barbados","The Middle East"],"question":"Pad Thai is a dish that is most associated with which part of the world?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Switzerland","incorrectAnswers":["Kazakhstan","Ghana","Senegal"],"question":"Which of these countries has white on its flag?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"New Orleans Saints","incorrectAnswers":["New Orleans Flames","New Orleans Dolphins","New Orleans Cardinals"],"question":"Which of these is an American Football team based in New Orleans?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The records in tree rings","incorrectAnswers":["Muscles","Minerals","Venereal diseases"],"question":"What is dendrochronology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Sterilize them","incorrectAnswers":["Dispose of them","Repair them","Sharpen them"],"question":"What is an autoclave designed to do to surgical instruments in a medical lab?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Marie Antoinette","incorrectAnswers":["Queen Victoria","Abraham Lincoln","Cleopatra"],"question":"Who is reputed to have said said: \"Let them eat cake\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pat Benatar","incorrectAnswers":["Blondie","Patti Smith","Patti Cake$"],"question":"Patricia Andrzejewski Is The Real Name Of Which Singer","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Cavatappi","incorrectAnswers":["Orecchiette","Penne","Ravioli"],"question":"Which pasta's name means 'Corkscrews'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Verona","incorrectAnswers":["Venice","Florence","Rome"],"question":"What Italian city is the setting for the opening of 'Romeo & Juliet'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"St. Basil's Cathedral","incorrectAnswers":["Peter and Paul Fortress","Kazan Cathedral","Winter Palace"],"question":"Which of these iconic Russian buildings is located in Moscow?","difficulty":"medium"},